<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Vox -  All</title>
    <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52517/voxv.png</icon>
    <updated>2019-02-11T16:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
    <link type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/" rel="alternate"/>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T16:00:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T16:00:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>I’m a geophysicist. My signature fieldwork uniform is bright pink. </title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HxPrR6k8eh80EdFePV2ISO5OBWI=/0x0:4379x3284/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63036390/GettyImages_170046513.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;Pink won’t fix the systemic sexism in the sciences, but it also won’t hinder the development of anyone’s skills. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="9rIEqe"&gt;My boots for fieldwork are the essence of pragmatism, with tall shafts, sharp metal spikes for grip on slippery forest floors, and steel toes for safety, all in bland navy. They’re pure function, with no leeway to form. That is, until you get to the glittery pink laces.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ejGjHL"&gt;I’m a field geophysicist. Basically, that means I go out into remote areas, ride around in helicopters to reach even more remote mountain peaks and glacial valleys, then spread out an array of delicate electronics and hope it doesn’t all short out in the rain or get chewed on by a bear. I hit a big red button to trigger anything from an electric shock to an explosion, listen carefully for how that signal gets warped by the Earth, then invert that data to pry into subsurface secrets. It’s a fascinating mix of James Bond villain and MacGyver, a blend of geek and jock, and the perfect job for someone who loves the beauty of math but can’t resist the call of the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="iusEmD"&gt;It’s also one of the many science fields where women are a rare sight.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="cBajMJ"&gt;I was always going to stand out among the burly, gruff men who make up most of the transient inhabitants of the mines and exploration camps I go to for gigs. But it didn’t take me long to embrace pink as my signature color during fieldwork, standing out even more prominently in a sea of drab olive greens, matte blacks, muddy browns, and sharp neon orange high-vis gear.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
            &lt;img alt="Mika wearing her bright uniform" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iaZtwAzXiYHMoSSRCZN4mac6NKo=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13752502/unnamed.jpg"&gt;
            &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Mika McKinnon&lt;/cite&gt;
            &lt;figcaption&gt;The author in her signature color. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="mzESh2"&gt;My foray into pink field gear started in my toolbag as an anti-theft deterrent after one too many of my field knives never made it back from lending out to crew for stripping and splicing wire. I bought a pink knife as an experiment, and when it survived an entire gig, I loaded up on pink flagging, purple electrical and duct tape, and even dusky rose pink gloves. I grew even more excited when I realized how clearly pink stood out when I inevitably dropped a tool in the musty detritus of a forest floor.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="bEiPGw"&gt;The next phase of my evolution was a hardhat.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="32am0X"&gt;Hardhats on work sites follow a color code: white for supervisors, green for safety officers, yellow for construction, and so on. Pink falls nowhere on this scale, although some sites have a loaner pink hardhat to bestow as punishment for the forgetful, careless, or simply new. I don’t see wearing a feminine-coded color as punishment and I like being visible at long distances, so on went the pink hardhat.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ElfC2v"&gt;Then one of my coworkers told me, “I’d never wear a pink hardhat because it would instantly undermine my credibility.” Yes, I was wearing a pink hardhat at the time. Yes, she, too, was one of the few women in this rough-and-tumble industry, although her coping method seemed to be blending in to the dominant culture while mine was aggressively pink confrontation. Yes, I wrote down the exact phrasing to never, ever forget it.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Q4mM2J"&gt;The next day, I laced pink glittery laces into my steel-toed rubber calk boots.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="OGGVEs"&gt;After chatting with helicopter pilots, my signature pink transitioned from ornery defiance into the smart safety choice. Pink is gorgeously, delightfully, perfectly visible from long distances (or when piled in a heap of muddy rubber work boots). It doesn’t matter if I’m working at a mine, in a forest, on a glacier, or any other landscape — unless I’m in a dense field of wildflowers, nothing in nature is going to camouflage me when I’m in bright pink.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="SgSSYm"&gt;Pink had one last unexpected benefit: My glittery laces and eye-searing hardhat became a filter on the types of people I encountered in the field. If the hint of whimsy brought an involuntary smile to their lips, we’d work well together. But if they couldn’t help but express their scorn, I learned up front who thought the mere touch of a feminine color inhibited competence. I waved a pink flag antagonizing those who resented having a woman in the field running a geophysics crew, and when they charged and snorted their displeasure, I could strategize coping techniques to get the job done instead of getting blindsided by their sexism later.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
            &lt;img alt="Boots with glittery laces" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p0ZVTfyeahrNoCwRDJn35s0eV1w=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13752505/unnamed_1.jpg"&gt;
            &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Mika McKinnon&lt;/cite&gt;
            &lt;figcaption&gt;The author’s glittery boots. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="TesIc1"&gt;The very reasons pink is met with such hostility during fieldwork is the same reason it smothers even the science section of toy stores. Pink is a &lt;a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/when-did-girls-start-wearing-pink-1370097/"&gt;gender-coded color&lt;/a&gt;, one first relegated to boys as a paler red far too passionate for little ladies, then just a few decades later assigned to girls and declared hue non grata for those wishing to project the manliest of manly aesthetics. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="bUyrfR"&gt;While I’ve yet to understand how children’s toys can be “for” boys or “for” girls unless they’re being used in an adults-only manner, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/aug/05/girls-aisle-sexist-toys-clothes"&gt;marketers have no such hardships&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://slate.com/human-interest/2012/11/pink-science-a-travesty-with-a-history.html"&gt;Science kits “for” girls are inevitably emblazoned with pink&lt;/a&gt;. At best, these cotton-candy kits contain the same experiments as the blue “boys” kits, possibly each plastic piece within pinkified to match the exterior case. At worst, the blue box of volcanoes and goop is mirrored by a hot pink case promising DIY cosmetics and soap. &lt;a href="https://mashable.com/2016/01/24/coding-girls-pink/"&gt;This pinkification extends beyond the toy store and into campaigns ostensibly to recruit girls into science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM)&lt;/a&gt; as though a bubbly pink font were the only obstacle to why women are so painfully underrepresented in senior levels of these fields.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="AYUWZS"&gt;But pink is just a color.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="m3X5Fy"&gt;Pinkificiation of science isn’t some panacea that will fix systemic sexism that convinces little girls they aren’t good at math, nor will it remove the institutionalized harassment that &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/women-in-stem-1.4564384&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1549982665704000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGpF-JlusKvDhBUmy1Pxq0-1Ahqhg"&gt;drives women out of science as the years of injustice grind them down&lt;/a&gt;. Pops of pink may soothe my raging soul as a quiet rebellion, but it won’t erase the cultural attitudes driving me to muffle my screams of frustration into a rictus smile that passes for polite.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="c0duXF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I can wear pink and still be a scientist, even one doing fieldwork&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="6UlaFY"&gt;Pink doesn’t inhibit critical thinking skills. It doesn’t destroy analytical ability. As long as you’re using your personal protective equipment properly, it doesn’t impact data collection. I can wear pink and still be a scientist, even one doing fieldwork.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="dsF2rW"&gt;I don’t dream of a future where every scientist and engineer wears pink when doing their work, irrespective of gender identity. Instead, I dream of a future where we finally realize aesthetics and competency are independent factors in who we are, where personal fashion choices — glam, punk, haute couture, rockabilly, bohemian, preppy, princess, or anything else — are independent of perceptions of scientific competency. The pinkification to lure girls into science, technology, engineering, and mathematics is deeply sexist, but so are attitudes that declare feminine choices are incompatible with being smart or doing science.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="haneRq"&gt;And if someone thinks pink undermines my credibility?&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="c-end-para" id="k2PMy1"&gt;That’s their baggage, not mine.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="eOuD2s"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="kBX4hx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/2/11/18220764/mika-mckinnon-stem-pink-uniform-sexism"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/2/11/18220764/mika-mckinnon-stem-pink-uniform-sexism</id>
        <author>
            <name>Mika McKinnon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T15:50:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T15:50:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>The past 72 hours of Brexit ridiculousness, explained</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="British Prime Minister Theresa May meets with European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker on February 7, 2019." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vM5rBL46F5z-qSsDf1qHHwc8BlE=/92x0:4956x3648/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63036493/1094820920.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;The EU and the UK are still talking, and Prime Minister Theresa May will update Parliament about Brexit on Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="zdEu4k"&gt;There are less &lt;a href="https://howmanydaystill.com/its/brexit-6"&gt;than 50 days to go&lt;/a&gt; until &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/15/18184284/brexit-vote-theresa-may-no-confidence-500-words"&gt;Brexit&lt;/a&gt; officially happens, and the United Kingdom still hasn’t approved a final divorce deal with the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="15BbUQ"&gt;The UK remains stuck in the same bind it’s been in for the past few weeks — &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/29/18202210/brexit-parliament-vote-backstop-theresa-may"&gt;unable to stomach&lt;/a&gt; Prime Minister Theresa May’s current Brexit withdrawal agreement, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/06/world/europe/theresa-may-brexit-tusk-brussels-backstop.html"&gt;seeking concessions from the EU&lt;/a&gt; its officials are &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/uk-britain-eu-juncker/juncker-says-eu-wont-reopen-brexit-deal-britains-may-knows-that-idUSKCN1PV20X"&gt;probably not willing to give&lt;/a&gt;, and failing to agree on little except the desire to avoid leaving the EU without a deal on March 29, 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="nhBnpB"&gt;This next week could change things — or maybe not. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="hKpRnk"&gt;We’ll find out a bit more about where things stand on Tuesday, when Prime Minister Theresa May &lt;a href="https://uk.reuters.com/article/uk-britain-eu-feb14-factbox/factbox-brexit-what-will-happen-in-the-british-parliament-on-february-14-idUKKCN1PZ0LD"&gt;gives an update to the UK Parliament&lt;/a&gt; on the status of Brexit. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="W0lEco"&gt;After May gives her update, Parliament will draft and debate amendments to try to give themselves more say over the Brexit process. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="TEwODK"&gt;The vote on those amendments is currently scheduled for Thursday. But that’s not the so-called “meaningful vote” in which Parliament will vote (yet again) on an actual final Brexit agreement.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;That probably won’t happen &lt;a href="http://www.cityam.com/273009/theresa-may-promises-mps-another-brexit-vote-end-february"&gt;until the end of February&lt;/a&gt;, a mere month away from the March 29 Brexit deadline. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="gHfimm"&gt;Time is running out. So are the available options — and the Brexit impasse is &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-02-11/u-k-economy-wilts-as-brexit-jitters-hit-business-investment"&gt;already taking a toll&lt;/a&gt; on the British economy. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="LrvsPQ"&gt;There’s a lot of stuff going on, so to catch up and keep track of what’s happening next, here’s a breakdown of the past (roughly) 72 hours in Brexit news. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="6yk7wX"&gt;Lots and lots of talking — mostly past one another — in Brussels and London&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="AsaVb9"&gt;Prime Minister Theresa May met with EU leaders last week, her first trip to Brussels since the UK Parliament &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/29/18202210/brexit-parliament-vote-backstop-theresa-may"&gt;voted on January 29&lt;/a&gt; that she should renegotiate elements of the unpopular Brexit deal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Zv8oYn"&gt;May was specifically seeking to find a new solution to the “Irish backstop,” the part of the Brexit deal that is intended to avoid any border checks between Northern Ireland (which is part of the UK) and Ireland (which is an EU member state) springing up as a result of Brexit. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="93Rezz"&gt;Hardline Brexit supporters in May’s Conservative Party see the current arrangement May has worked out with the EU — which would require the UK to follow the same customs regulations as the EU — as potentially trapping the UK within the EU indefinitely, and they want her to come up with a better solution. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="xr63CS"&gt;The EU, though, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/29/18202210/brexit-parliament-vote-backstop-theresa-may"&gt;has said it will not renegotiate&lt;/a&gt; the backstop, as it’s part of the painstakingly negotiated withdrawal plan they’ve already agreed to and have no incentive to reopen. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="dGr7nw"&gt;But May still has to try, and she &lt;a href="https://www.standard.co.uk/news/politics/brexit-news-latest-jeanclaude-juncker-tells-theresa-may-deal-will-not-be-renegotiated-a4060391.html"&gt;met Thursday with&lt;/a&gt; EU leaders in Brussels and &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-northern-ireland-47161550"&gt;Irish Prime Minister Leo Varadkar in Dublin on Friday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="pwu6Ez"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This evening an Taoiseach, Leo Varadkar and Prime Minister, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/theresa_may?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@theresa_may&lt;/a&gt; met at Farmleigh House in Dublin to discuss the ongoing political impasse in Northern Ireland and the latest Brexit developments following their respective engagements in Belfast and Brussels. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Brexit?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Brexit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/MN8GKnAqzH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/MN8GKnAqzH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— MerrionStreet.ie (@merrionstreet) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/merrionstreet/status/1093986278985613314?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="409vdP"&gt;After the talks in Brussels, May and EU Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker issued a joint statement in which they described their discussions as “robust but constructive” and &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2019/02/07/uk/theresa-may-brussels-brexit-gbr-intl/index.html"&gt;recommitted&lt;/a&gt; to finding a way to get a Brexit deal through Parliament that also works for the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="pndC9n"&gt;European Council President Donald Tusk (who drew the ire of Brexiteers earlier last week for saying there was a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/video/2019/feb/06/special-place-in-hell-donald-tusk-derides-brexiters-without-a-plan-video"&gt;“special place in hell”&lt;/a&gt; for those who promoted Brexit without a plan) also said the UK and EU would keep talking.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="vvEJMK"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Meeting PM &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/theresa_may?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@theresa_may&lt;/a&gt; on how to overcome impasse on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/brexit?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#brexit&lt;/a&gt;. Still no breakthrough in sight. Talks will continue. &lt;a href="https://t.co/vn2CVybc1j"&gt;pic.twitter.com/vn2CVybc1j&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Donald Tusk (@eucopresident) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eucopresident/status/1093535048454860800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 7, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="SjV8FB"&gt;And Varadkar &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-northern-ireland-47161550"&gt;told May&lt;/a&gt; the Irish government and the rest of the EU believe the backstop has to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="nuZy1y"&gt;So, nothing much has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="qeeT7o"&gt;But talks on this seemingly intractable issue will continue this week, regardless of how futile they might be. UK Brexit Secretary Stephen Barclay &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/11/the-two-year-hunt-for-the-brexit-unicorn"&gt;will meet with EU negotiators on Monday&lt;/a&gt;, bringing recommendations from a Conservative MP working group on “alternative arrangements” &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/11/the-two-year-hunt-for-the-brexit-unicorn"&gt;that the EU probably won’t go for&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="TY0iFj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/11/barnier-says-britain-must-give-ground-to-break-brexit-impasse"&gt;Michel Barnier, the EU’s chief Brexit negotiator&lt;/a&gt;, has said ahead of these meetings that the EU won’t reopen the backstop issue, but that it’s willing to rework the political declaration, which lays out the commitment for a future EU-UK relationship after Brexit. The political declaration is purposefully broad, but the EU has said it’s willing to make it more specific — if the UK can say for sure what it wants. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="sM6QlA"&gt;“Something has got to give,” &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/11/barnier-says-britain-must-give-ground-to-break-brexit-impasse"&gt;Barnier told reporters Monday&lt;/a&gt;. It’s just not clear at this point if anything will. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="9cmJ8p"&gt;May to Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn: Thanks for the feedback, but no&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="Zccyb0"&gt;One of the (many) criticisms May has faced during this whole years-long Brexit negotiation debacle has been her apparent unwillingness to build cross-party support for Brexit. Critics say she has failed to get buy-in from moderate members of both her own Conservative Party and from the opposition Labour Party, all of whom want to avoid the economic and political shock of a hard Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="dQ5vJJ"&gt;But there was a glimmer of hope of a possible breakthrough last week, when May and Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/jan/30/jeremy-corbyn-to-meet-theresa-may-for-brexit-talks"&gt;met for private discussions&lt;/a&gt; last month. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ktUqmv"&gt;Corbyn is in a bind because &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-corbyn-second-referendum-labour-theresa-may-deal-commons-letter-a8773671.html"&gt;he doesn’t want to support&lt;/a&gt; a second referendum — putting another vote on Brexit to the British people — which many in his party want him to do if May can’t close the deal. And May is in a bind trying to seek concessions from the EU on the backstop that they’re not willing to give. So maybe, the thinking went, the two could figure something out. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="UC5L2T"&gt;So they sat down to talk. Afterward, Corbyn &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jeremycorbyn/status/1093286577239965696"&gt;followed up on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/06/corbyn-lays-out-labours-terms-for-backing-may-on-brexit"&gt;presenting May with some conditions&lt;/a&gt; under which Labour would support a Brexit deal. The demands revolved around that political declaration I mentioned earlier. Corbyn asked May to offer &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/06/corbyn-lays-out-labours-terms-for-backing-may-on-brexit"&gt;more concrete commitments&lt;/a&gt; on what a future EU-UK relationship will look like. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="xLyHpB"&gt;Specifically, Corbyn &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/06/corbyn-lays-out-labours-terms-for-backing-may-on-brexit"&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; that a commitment be made to keep the UK involved in a customs union with the EU&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(which means the UK would follow the same customs rules as the rest of the EU).  That’s something May has previously ruled out, as membership in a customs union means the UK can’t make its own trade deals.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="csdL7u"&gt;Many moderates and business-minded Conservatives would probably go for such an arrangement — though it would likely split May’s party, with hardline Brexiteers opposing it. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="kZAsrP"&gt;But May responded to Corbyn’s proposals on Sunday with a letter that basically said “Thanks, but no thanks.” May &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/10/brexit-mps-will-have-another-say-by-end-of-month-says-minister"&gt;objected&lt;/a&gt; to membership in a customs union again because of trade deals. “I am not clear why you believe it would be preferable to seek a say in future EU trade deals rather than the ability to strike our own deals?” May wrote to Corbyn. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="RyfhPb"&gt;May did offer some commitments on other issues Corbyn raised, including labor and environmental rights, but this is far from the game-changer in the Brexit debate some were hoping for. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="B4NRSo"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NEW: Theresa May letter to Jeremy Corbyn&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Luke warm defence leaving customs union cd discomfort brexiteers  &lt;br&gt;- TM admits frictionless trade will be “negotiating challenge”  &lt;br&gt;- Leaves door open to working with Corbyn: but how will more brexit inclined Tories feel about this?  &lt;a href="https://t.co/S0A9f02cY7"&gt;pic.twitter.com/S0A9f02cY7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sam Coates Times (@SamCoatesTimes) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SamCoatesTimes/status/1094725247075565569?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="Vuto1q"&gt;Some read May’s letter &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6634c140-2df5-11e9-ba00-0251022932c8"&gt;as not totally ruling out a customs&lt;/a&gt; arrangement, but &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2019/feb/11/brexit-theresa-may-rules-out-jeremy-corbyn-customs-union-plan-rory-stewart"&gt;May’s spokesperson&lt;/a&gt; dashed any lingering optimism on Monday: “We are absolutely clear on this: we’re not considering Jeremy Corbyn’s customs proposals; we’re not considering any proposals to remain in the customs union. We must have our own, independent trade policy.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="VksLUe"&gt;Brexit might already be hurting the UK economy &lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="mXx006"&gt;It turns out that spending two years negotiating a Brexit deal and still not coming up with a solution hasn’t been particularly great for businesses in the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="PhDABm"&gt;The uncertainty over Brexit delivered Britain its worst economic numbers since 2012. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/feb/11/manufacturing-slump-puts-uk-economy-into-reverse-as-brexit-looms"&gt;According to the UK’s Office for National Statistics,&lt;/a&gt; economic growth slowed &lt;a href="https://www.apnews.com/360d72f0e8404a50875166c44c7bbebc"&gt;to just .02 percent&lt;/a&gt; in the last quarter of 2018. Business investment also fell for the fourth quarter straight, &lt;a href="https://www.apnews.com/360d72f0e8404a50875166c44c7bbebc"&gt;according to the AP,&lt;/a&gt; which hasn’t happened since 2009, during the global financial crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="fujMSe"&gt;Philip Hammond, the chancellor of the Exchequer (the UK equivalent of the Treasury secretary), &lt;a href="https://news.sky.com/story/hammond-must-find-extra-billions-if-austerity-is-to-end-11634232"&gt;told Sky News&lt;/a&gt; that Brexit alone wasn’t responsible for the economic slowdown, but acknowledged that it still carried some of the blame. “There is no doubt that our economy is being overshadowed by the uncertainty created by the Brexit process,” &lt;a href="https://news.sky.com/story/hammond-must-find-extra-billions-if-austerity-is-to-end-11634232"&gt;he said.&lt;/a&gt; “The sooner we can resolve that the better, and the quicker we can get back to more robust growth in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="gFBQy9"&gt;The economic data echoes &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/bank-of-england-set-to-hold-rates-as-it-seeks-brexit-clarity/2019/02/07/d3b238fa-2a95-11e9-906e-9d55b6451eb4_story.html?utm_term=.43db390fed54"&gt;a warning&lt;/a&gt; last week from the Bank of England (the UK’s central bank) that the “fog of Brexit” is forcing businesses to rethink investment and households to rethink their spending. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="RWVbGL"&gt;“Although many companies are stepping up their contingency planning, the economy as a whole is still not yet prepared for a no-deal, no-transition exit,” Bank of England Governor Mark Carney &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/bank-of-england-set-to-hold-rates-as-it-seeks-brexit-clarity/2019/02/07/d3b238fa-2a95-11e9-906e-9d55b6451eb4_story.html?utm_term=.43db390fed54"&gt;said last week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="xSzBs2"&gt;Of course, with less than 50 days to go and no plan in sight, the economy will continue to react. And if a deal can’t be reached, the economic consequences will be catastrophic. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="JQhMZz"&gt;May moves up her update to Tuesday. Will Parliament step up?&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="8lRGtb"&gt;May will deliver an update to members of Parliament on Brexit on Tuesday and try to win support for her current strategy — which basically just involves trying to win more support for her deal, with changes to the Irish backstop. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="SSaFuL"&gt;May will likely include a report on her &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-northern-ireland-47161550"&gt;visit with EU leaders&lt;/a&gt; last week and any progress her government has made on the backstop. Which means she probably won’t have a lot to say. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="1twfby"&gt;Members of Parliament, however, will get a chance to respond, and either support her current course or introduce amendments that could help Parliament take more control of the process. They’ll vote on those amendments Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="HpayFZ"&gt;If this sounds somewhat familiar, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/29/18202210/brexit-parliament-vote-backstop-theresa-may"&gt;it should&lt;/a&gt;. Parliament &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/28/18200666/brexit-parliament-vote-amendments-brady-cooper"&gt;did something similar last month,&lt;/a&gt; and it’s possible that many amendments similar to those &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/28/18200666/brexit-parliament-vote-amendments-brady-cooper"&gt;that failed or got dropped last time&lt;/a&gt; will get another vote, including one that would have forced May to get a Brexit deadline extension if she couldn’t pass a deal by a certain date. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="RgwqxC"&gt;But Parliament mostly punted last time: Instead of taking control, it &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/1/29/18202210/brexit-parliament-vote-backstop-theresa-may"&gt;sent May back to Brussels&lt;/a&gt; on this doomed mission to renegotiate the backstop. It also passed an amendment saying that Parliament rejects leaving the EU without a deal, but it wasn’t binding, so it didn’t actually force May’s government to do anything. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="9kwXt2"&gt;Whether things will be different this time around is still unclear. Labour MPs have said they’ll introduce an amendment &lt;a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/2019/0210/1028687-brexit-labour-vote/"&gt;that will demand May puts any Brexit deal to a vote by February 26&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="bsSE2R"&gt;Yet members of Parliament are still bitterly divided, and May’s likely to make the case to her Conservative party that she’ll deliver to Parliament if she just has a little more time. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="7m7oE9"&gt;But despite what May might say, when it comes to Brexit, time &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rIE2GAqnFGw"&gt;isn’t really on anyone’s side&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/2/11/18220184/brexit-irish-backstop-theresa-may-eu-parliament"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/world/2019/2/11/18220184/brexit-irish-backstop-theresa-may-eu-parliament</id>
        <author>
            <name>Jen Kirby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T15:20:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T15:20:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>Utah Republicans have officially blocked their state’s voter-approved Medicaid expansion</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="Supporters of a voter-approved measure to fully expand Medicaid gather at the Utah State Capitol January 28, 2019, in Salt Lake City." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/APXkWPWLAyOTMZaBHMtzwD0Kmdg=/197x0:4910x3535/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63036157/AP_19028847184661.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;The GOP’s crusade to scale back Utah’s Medicaid expansion puts coverage for thousands of people at risk.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="8WjvMX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/11/6/18047776/medicaid-expansion-vote-election-idaho-montana-nebraska-utah"&gt;Utah voters decided to expand Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; under the Affordable Care Act in November. But the Republican legislature is scaling back the voter-approved plan.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="rdbbmz"&gt;The Republican legislature has passed legislation that would, in effect, replace &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/11/7/18055848/medicaid-expansion-idaho-nebraska-utah"&gt;the voter-approved Medicaid expansion&lt;/a&gt; with a more limited version that would actually cover fewer people while spending more money in the first few years. The bill passed both chambers with a two-thirds majority. It now heads to Republican Gov. Gary Herbert, who is expected to sign it.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Y3u7eu"&gt;GOP lawmakers are making a big bet: that they will be the first state to receive approval from the Trump administration for &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/4/2/17189878/utah-medicare-expansion-waiver-massachusetts-voxcare"&gt;a partial Medicaid expansion&lt;/a&gt;. Originally, the Senate-passed legislation stipulated the entire expansion would have been repealed if the feds rejected Utah’s plan, reversing the will of the voters completely. But the state House, facing intense pressure, changed the bill at the last minute so if the Trump administration does reject partial expansion, the full Medicaid expansion as originally approved by voters would take effect instead.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="D16Uxv"&gt;Expansion supporters have still condemned Republicans for needlessly interceding to institute a scaled-back version of expansion, one will come at a higher initial cost to the state, after Utahns voted decisively just three months ago to expand Medicaid and extend health coverage to tens of thousands of vulnerable people.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="aHBj2H"&gt;“The legislature is trampling on the clear will of voters,” Jonathan Schleifer, executive director of the Fairness Project, which helped push the ballot referendum, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="9yPXcm"&gt;Voters approved full Medicaid expansion. Republicans only want to go partway. &lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="qx1vux"&gt;The ballot measure approved by the voters by a 53-47 margin was unambiguous: The state would expand Medicaid to 138 percent of the federal poverty level — about $16,800 for an individual or $29,700 for a family of three — as prescribed in the health care law. It would cover 150,000 of Utah’s poorest people. The state’s share of Medicaid expansion spending (about 10 percent, with the feds picking up the other 90) was to be paid for by an increase in the sales tax.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="zJKMrx"&gt;The legislation approved by Republicans would repeal the ballot referendum and replace it with new provisions to extend Medicaid eligibility up to only 100 percent of the poverty level and the state would have to initially pick up 30 percent of the cost. About 60,000 fewer people would be covered, and Utah would spend $72 million over the next two years. The bill is very similar to &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/4/2/17189878/utah-medicare-expansion-waiver-massachusetts-voxcare"&gt;a plan Utah Republicans approved last year&lt;/a&gt; for a partial Medicaid expansion that did not actually take effect.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="6HVpbG"&gt;Full Medicaid expansion was to be covered entirely by the sales tax increase that was already passed as part of the ballot referendum. That tax was pegged to an earlier estimate of the full expansion’s costs over the first two years, but the state government has since released a new projection that forecasts a $10.4 million shortfall in year three, which Republican leaders have then used to justify pursuing their partial expansion, saying it’s more fiscally responsible. Still, even with that updated estimate, their plan will come with a higher price tag at first.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="unCVwZ"&gt;The only way the Republican plan would save the state money is if they received federal approval to get a 90-10 match, something that hasn’t ever happened before, may not be legally permissible, and is the subject of fierce debate in the Trump administration. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="vPuI2y"&gt;Without such approval, the expansion would have been automatically repealed under the Senate-approved iteration of this plan. The House revised the plan so that, if the Trump administration rejects their partial expansion plan, the full Medicaid expansion that the voters had approved in the first place would go into effect instead.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="bjUlEL"&gt;Utah Republicans are betting that they can get Trump’s sign-off on their plan&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="iH2ETe"&gt;Two states, Arkansas and Massachusetts, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/8/10/16127264/voxcare-waiver-really-big-deal-medicaid"&gt;have already asked the Trump administration to let them shift to a partial Medicaid expansion&lt;/a&gt;, covering people up to 100 percent of the poverty line. People above that threshold would have to buy coverage through the private insurance marketplaces set up under the health care law.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="LCRTjW"&gt;But those states haven’t received federal approval, with Trump’s health department remaining silent on this question. As &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/30/us/politics/trump-medicaid-partial-expansion.html"&gt;the New York Times’s Robert Pear reported last summer&lt;/a&gt;, administration officials have hotly debated the expansion question, with some arguing in its favor (to head off states like Utah deciding to fully expand Medicaid) while others refuse to do anything proactive that would help expand Obamacare’s coverage to more people.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="bk07UI"&gt;Utah Republicans have nevertheless sounded confident about their plan’s prospects in Washington, stating outright that they have assurances from anonymous Trump officials that the waiver to get the 90 percent federal match would be approved. As UtahPolicy.com, a local news outlet, &lt;a href="https://www.utahpolicy.com/index.php/features/today-at-utah-policy/19324-will-utah-get-a-medicaid-waiver-for-limited-expansion-republicans-in-the-legislature-are-confident-it-will-happen"&gt;reported this week&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p id="0c2nw6"&gt;One Republican lawmaker involved in the planning for SB96 tells UtahPolicy.com that they met with a top official from CMS (The Centers for Medicaid and Medicare Service) two days before the start of this year’s session. During the meeting, they were told CMS is developing a “special waiver” for states to give them the 90/10 cost split if they implement limited Medicaid expansion, even if the plan includes caps or work requirements as Utah’s plan does. The lawmaker asked that we withhold their name.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="y6bDrt"&gt;Republicans say privately they’re extremely confident that Utah, and other states, will be awarded this new waiver sometime in the 12 months following implementation of their Medicaid expansion, allowing the 90/10 cost breakdown while giving health care to fewer people than the full expansion under Prop. 3. That means SB96 is essentially a “bridge” program to fund expansion until that happens. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p id="B3ShkN"&gt;Based on the Utah bill text, GOP lawmakers seem to think they’ve found a loophole: By accepting spending caps (&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/1/17/18186676/government-shutdown-medicaid-block-grants"&gt;the long-rumored goal of top Trump health officials&lt;/a&gt;) for their Medicaid expansion, they can get federal approval where Arkansas and Massachusetts, which actually sought to scale back from full to partial expansion, have not.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="DQMfS1"&gt;But Eliot Fishman, who worked on Medicaid waivers under President Barack Obama and now works at Families USA, said this provision is a fundamental misreading of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services’ discretion under federal law. If Utah can get a federal waiver to cover somebody in poverty and receive a 90 percent match, then Massachusetts must be able to receive the deal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="zo0dOo"&gt;“What they definitely cannot do is say: We are exercising state-by-state discretion based on other criteria,” he told me, “which is what Utah seems to be assuming.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="LnnJdR"&gt;Massachusetts could then sue if Utah’s waiver is approved. Litigation was likely to follow anyway from supporters of the ballot referendum if Utah Republicans move ahead with their plan. The state could be walking into a legal landmine — all in the name of extending health insurance to fewer people than the plan already approved by the state’s voters, and at a higher initial cost.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="sSJo0v"&gt;But the Republican legislature still pushed onward in the hope of beating back Obamacare’s unlikely victory last fall in this conservative state. Health insurance for thousands of the state’s most vulnerable residents hangs in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="STnyDo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/2/11/18220721/utah-medicaid-expansion-prop-3-sb96"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/2/11/18220721/utah-medicaid-expansion-prop-3-sb96</id>
        <author>
            <name>Dylan Scott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T15:10:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T15:10:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>Ariana Grande and Donald Glover weren’t at the Grammys, but their weird cartoon ads were</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="Ariana Grande as Memoji." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QSOpHn9LiM0xWmxsLLAi_0SASUI=/386x0:2437x1538/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63036078/Screen_Shot_2019_02_11_at_2.32.44_PM.0.png" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;Apple and Google battled to have the strangest cartoon pop star. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="dhbb1s"&gt;Sunday night during the Grammys, awards were handed out. But during the commercial breaks, Wiz Khalifa &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCYrx7f8QvhZKKh7a0815UuA"&gt;ate Oreos&lt;/a&gt; with his son, Serena Williams &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D_QRuCBmPr4"&gt;drove a fancy car&lt;/a&gt;, and Ariana Grande’s disembodied head sang “7 rings,” the song that Grammys producer Ken Ehrlich &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-47168089"&gt;supposedly barred her&lt;/a&gt; from performing onstage, in a new commercial for Apple’s Memoji feature. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Ub28E9"&gt;“Look at my neck!” the cartoon Ariana Grande ordered, despite not having a neck. Similar commercials were made featuring the Grammy-nominated country duo &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7yPJXGO2Dcw"&gt;Florida Georgia Line&lt;/a&gt; and 2018 Best New Artist nominee &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qgy6LaO3SB0"&gt;Khalid&lt;/a&gt;. The real Ariana Grande won best pop vocal album for &lt;em&gt;Sweetener&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/2/10/18219755/grammys-2019-ariana-grande-apple-music"&gt;wore a Cinderella ball gown&lt;/a&gt; to sit on the floor of her own house. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="c71LgC"&gt;But what exactly is this ad even for? What are these little cartoon heads?&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="6Cf8zS"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.2493%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YxLCwfA1cLw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="xoEy3S"&gt;Memoji is an iteration on Animoji, the feature that allowed iPhone X owners to put their own voices into an array of different animal heads (or the poop emoji). These are customized Animojis that are supposed to look like the sender — essentially the same thing as Snapchat’s Bitmoji, except they move. They’re only available on the four latest iPhones — X, XS, XS Max, and XR — because they require Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/15/16658074/iphone-x-face-id-app-developers-3d-the-future"&gt;relatively new TrueDepth camera tech&lt;/a&gt; to do accurate face mapping. You can send videos up to 30 seconds long of your Memoji in iMessage, if that seems more fun than a typical voice note. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="dYIS2r"&gt;Donald Glover, who won Song of the Year and Record of the Year for his single “This is America,” released under his musical moniker Childish Gambino, also stayed home from the ceremony. He appeared only briefly, in a prerecorded clip already released &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Btn_vMaFgKT/"&gt;on his Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, as himself and as an animated version of himself having a dance battle with each other in a commercial for Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/9/17955584/google-ar-stickers-playground-rebrand-pixel-3"&gt;Playmoji feature&lt;/a&gt;. Playmoji’s &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/products/google-ar-vr/see-your-world-differently-playground-and-google-lens-pixel-3/"&gt;Playground&lt;/a&gt; app was originally called AR Stickers, and uses Google’s augmented reality tech to put dancing celebrities into photos and videos taken with any of its Pixel phones. Google is particularly proud of how lifelike Playmoji are, &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/playmoji-what-is-childish-gambino-google-ad-grammys-commercial-pixel-a8773381.html"&gt;emphasizing&lt;/a&gt; that they cast shadows and interact with light in realistic ways, and that they can even “[react] to your facial expressions in real time thanks to machine learning.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="Hz1XbZ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.2493%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dMu4HpT7xSM?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="2JFBVm"&gt;(Both are slightly better than Samsung’s AR Emoji, which debuted in February 2018 and were described &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/26/17052754/samsung-galaxy-s9-ar-emoji-mwc-2018"&gt;by The Verge’s Sam Byford&lt;/a&gt; as “kind of horrifying.”)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="lYEVhr"&gt;Trade publication AdAge &lt;a href="https://adage.com/article/news/apple-google-waged-a-grammys-ad-duel-wake-call/316601/"&gt;called the similar commercials&lt;/a&gt; an “ad duel,” citing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ndrewharman/status/1094780824631808000"&gt;one tweet&lt;/a&gt; that asked, “Am I the only one who was unaware of a great arms race in emoji tech?” These are sort of violent and dramatic metaphors (which I have echoed in my own subheadline solely because looking at two equally bizarre primetime commercials as a showdown between tech giants can be sort of fun on a Monday). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="MquHAP"&gt;Google has talked up the Pixel’s augmented reality and creativity features quite a bit, and presumably spent a pretty big chunk of change on the rights to Donald Glover’s … body and movements (both are &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2018/10/23/18010274/amy-winehouse-hologram-tour-controversy-technology"&gt;subject to copyright&lt;/a&gt;) in addition to the rights to his unreleased song “Human Sacrifice” plus however much he charges for his time. The incentive to shell out for the best emoji tech and a super-cool celebrity affiliation seems pretty obvious: Globally, most people own Android phones, but in the US, 82 percent of teenagers &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/82-percent-of-american-teens-own-an-iphone-piper-jaffray-survey-2018-10"&gt;prefer the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="eFYg1n"&gt;Apple already has cultural clout and a long-standing affiliation with the music industry, which makes its Grammys commercials kind of &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2018/10/31/18043714/apple-macbook-air-ipad-pro-announcement-brooklyn"&gt;redundant&lt;/a&gt; and maybe a little braggy — in that way, “7 rings” is an &lt;a href="http://bullet-point-boast"&gt;appropriately showy, bullet-point-boast&lt;/a&gt; choice of song! But the various Ariana Grande Memoji shown off in the ad don’t particularly look like her, and it’s just kind of absurd that a neckless blob talking about its “gleaming skin” is what America had to endure in the place of a live performance by Ariana Grande. In this battle, I have to say, I can’t choose a winner. (Actually, I can, and it’s &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/2/10/18219409/grammy-winners-2019-list"&gt;Kacey Musgraves&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="KJRNZK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="XhrVde"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/2/11/18220711/apple-ariana-grande-commercial-google-childish-gambino"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/2/11/18220711/apple-ariana-grande-commercial-google-childish-gambino</id>
        <author>
            <name>Kaitlyn Tiffany</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T14:30:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T14:30:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>Elizabeth Warren wants to ban the US from using nuclear weapons first</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="The first H-bomb explosion at Eniwetok Atoll in the Pacific" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bmf6wocIaRZqFfbe_7VTB4xUebA=/0x46:2805x2150/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63035529/3303720.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;This 12-word bill could change how we use nuclear weapons.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="tNsdn9"&gt;Two weeks ago, a major national security&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;bill was introduced in both houses of Congress — and hardly anyone noticed. That bill, introduced by Sen. Elizabeth Warren and House Armed Services Committee Chair &lt;a href="https://www.defensenews.com/congress/2018/11/14/smith-aims-to-scrap-trumps-nuclear-weapons-policy/"&gt;Adam Smith&lt;/a&gt;, was the &lt;a href="https://www.warren.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/No%20First%20Use%20Act.pdf"&gt;No First Use Act&lt;/a&gt;, and it aims to transform US nuclear weapons policy. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="feoXVF"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.warren.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/No%20First%20Use%20Act.pdf"&gt;text of the bill is a single sentence&lt;/a&gt;: “It is the policy of the United States to not use nuclear weapons first.” But that single sentence might be a really big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="yix9zW"&gt;Proponents argue that it’s the first step toward a better nuclear posture that will reduce the risk of an accident killing hundreds of thousands or spiraling into a global catastrophe. Nuclear weapons remain one of the biggest threats to human life. But opponents argue that it could instead destabilize international nuclear policy, driving arms races in countries that currently count on the US to protect them. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="v2tMdn"&gt;Taking either side at face value, it seems like one of the most important conversations we can be having. But nuclear security policy hasn’t featured much in mainstream politics, no matter how significant its implications — or maybe because they’re so significant, they feel a little ridiculous to engage with. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="LPsvpm"&gt;A nuclear war &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2018/10/19/17873822/nuclear-war-weapons-bombs-how-kill"&gt;could kill billions&lt;/a&gt;. Nuclear weapons have &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/1/25/18196416/nuclear-war-boris-yeltsin-1995-norway-rocket"&gt;nearly been deployed by mistake&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/9/26/17905796/nuclear-war-1983-stanislav-petrov-soviet-union"&gt;more than once&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah, sure, the Cold War’s over. But the conversation about safe nuclear policy really, really shouldn’t be. The No First Use Act won’t do much by itself, but if it’s a sign we’re ready to have a real conversation about how US policy can reduce the risk of a nuclear war, it’s a welcome one. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="5oLHb2"&gt;The roots of No First Use &lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="taq7ae"&gt;The one time the United States used nuclear weapons in war, it was to end a conflict being fought with conventional weapons. Since then, we’ve stopped thinking of nuclear weapons as just another tool in our toolbox in a conventional fight.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="HLTQ4L"&gt;“When we initially had the bomb, there were lots of questions about whether this was just something you could integrate into your arsenal,” Alex Wellerstein, who studies the history of nuclear weapons at the Stevens Institute of Technology, told me. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="WqpwoU"&gt;As the Soviet Union developed its own nuclear capabilities, and as expanding capabilities and early speculation about nuclear winter made it more obvious that the use of nuclear weapons could wipe out both countries, it stopped making any sense to treat nuclear weapons like just a bigger bomb. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="zjy7Ea"&gt;That’s when people first started pressing for US commitments not to use the bomb except in retaliation, if the Soviet Union bombed us. During the Cold War, this was a fringe stance. “People have advocated since the 1960s that people adopt a no first use policy,” Wellerstein said. “It’s usually been groups from outside the mainstream of policy.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="5JhWMH"&gt;The mainstream stance was — and still is — that we’d use nuclear weapons under extreme circumstances. It’s a deliberately nebulous position. Some experts worry that if we clarified, then enemies would feel emboldened&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to plan attacks, knowing our retaliation would be restrained to conventional weapons. Historically, we’ve also planned to use nuclear weapons in response to biological weapons. In the famous tapes released of his private White House conversations, President &lt;a href="http://www.councilforresponsiblegenetics.org/ViewPage.aspx?pageId=155"&gt;Nixon was uncommonly candid on why we can sign bioweapons treaties&lt;/a&gt;: “We’ll never use the damn germs. So what good is biological warfare as a deterrent? If someone uses germs on us, we’ll nuke ’em.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="uk8gzq"&gt;When the Cold War ended, that posture didn’t change. “There were efforts in the ’80s, the ’90s, the Obama administration to push the US toward a no first use policy,” Wellerstein said. The closest we came was under Obama, who put unusual emphasis on nuclear policy for a post-Cold-War president. But his administration ended up deciding against no first use. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="2wX8jX"&gt;“That had more to do with acclimating allies to the idea,” Alexandra Bell, the senior policy director at the Center for Arms Control and Non-Proliferation, told me. Even if the Obama administration’s strategists thought that no first use was the way to go, nuclear policy is so fraught that it’s important to have world leaders on board, and that takes some time. So the administration didn’t go that far. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="LSeGWs"&gt;The one-sentence bill that might change everything — or nothing&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="YiOPjY"&gt;Is changing US nuclear policy really as straightforward as passing a one-sentence bill declaring, “It is the policy of the United States not to use nuclear weapons first”? Well, no. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="TkB1yd"&gt;On its own, a declaration about US nuclear policy won’t be taken that seriously by anyone. In fact, critics of the bill argue, it might be taken seriously by our allies (making them nervous) and not by our enemies (making them bolder), which would be the worst of all possible worlds. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Ww78yd"&gt;Proponents of the bill agree that it won’t be taken seriously on its own. (The bill has been introduced before, and died without much discussion.) But they say that a change in official US policy would lead, down the road, to changes in which nuclear weapons we build and how we deploy them. That, unlike the bill itself, will be taken seriously. “It’s a political commitment,” Bell told me. “It signals to the world about where we want to go toward a deterrent-based posture. You need the policy and the force behind it.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="SIeDuL"&gt;But some worry that passing the bill won’t lead to the real changes — and, as a result, could actually cause harm.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“A declaration, without any attendant changes to the US’s ability to actually use nuclear weapons promptly, absent changes to the actual posture, alert levels, etc. — your adversaries won’t believe it,” Vipin Narang, an associate professor of political science at MIT, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oa2-9LMOFV4"&gt;argued&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="AdOn8G"&gt;“There’s a real concern here that your allies might. A big nonproliferation tool we’ve had at our disposal is extended deterrence. And for our allies, at least, not declaring one way or another that we might use nuclear weapons in their defense in a conventional attack against them may help reassurance at the margins,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="a8CB2c"&gt;To proponents of no first use, all of that means it’s finally time to make it happen. “We’ve come to a place where the US &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; adopt this kind of policy,” Bell told me. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="07HejF"&gt;And, perhaps more importantly, we’ve come to a place where the public is perhaps interested in thinking about nuclear security again. To a significant extent, interest in nuclear weapons as a topic died when the Cold War ended. The public doesn’t rank nuclear security among their &lt;a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/1675/most-important-problem.aspx"&gt;top considerations&lt;/a&gt;. It rarely gets much consideration in political campaigns or party platforms. Nuclear weapons could still kill us all — we just don’t think about this much.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="8Fybwq"&gt;Having Donald Trump in the White House might have changed that. “&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2016/12/01/no-one-can-stop-president-trump-from-using-nuclear-weapons-thats-by-design/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.d3e0775e813f"&gt;No one can stop President Trump from using nuclear weapons&lt;/a&gt;. That’s by design,” Wellerstein pointed out at the Washington Post three weeks after Trump was elected. That’s always been true, of course. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2017/11/17/16656856/trump-congress-nuclear-weapons-war"&gt;Any US president&lt;/a&gt; has the authority to order a nuclear strike on their own, though &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2017/11/17/16656856/trump-congress-nuclear-weapons-war"&gt;some experts argue&lt;/a&gt; that the military would disobey an illegal order. But with the president historically unpopular, and regarded by many as erratic, this longstanding truth has suddenly seemed especially troubling.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="lPkGas"&gt;“The silver lining of the Trump administration,” Bell told me, “is that people are reengaging in the conversation” about what the best policy for use of US nuclear weapons is. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="h34yUS"&gt;“We’re resurrecting an old conversation that has never really gotten that far,” Wellerstein said.  “And we’re doing it not to address an old problem — Can we lower the tensions of the arms race? — but to address a new problem, which is that we aren’t sure we can trust the US to do the right thing with its nukes.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="R343YX"&gt;In other words, many conversations about nuclear policy&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;assumed that our own leadership would be thoughtful and careful, and that we would use nuclear weapons only under the right circumstances. We’ve historically treated the important considerations in nuclear policy to be the reactions of our allies and adversaries. We haven’t put as much thought into how our nuclear policy could be better designed to hold our own leadership back from a terrible mistake. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="CLOoGS"&gt;Stopping a president from using nuclear weapons too soon&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="ToM4XL"&gt;Of course, if our real goal is reining in our own leadership, there might be even better ways to get there than no first use. No first use has a few major advantages as a national security stance. The first is its sheer simplicity — the bill is one sentence long. It reflects the understanding of US policy that many people already have — we don’t expect our government to be the first to escalate a conflict to nuclear weapons. It’s a starting point for “trying to get the legislative branch back in the business of nuclear policy,” Bell told me, and it’s particularly well-suited to that. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ZQUlqQ"&gt;But the policy with the best odds of getting traction probably isn’t the same as the ideal policy, and there are probably policies that address what Wellerstein calls the “bad president problem” better than no first use. If your aim is to prevent misuse, it might make more sense to add oversight — taking away the authority of the president to unilaterally launch nuclear weapons. It might make sense to explicitly set conditions — to decide, as a society, under what conditions we’d accept the use of nuclear weapons, and embed them into law. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="AXRVuA"&gt;But if those are unachievable — and they certainly look it — then we might realistically need to answer the question of whether no first use is better than nothing. If we can convince our allies that it doesn’t reflect a decrease in the American commitment to their safety — a real challenge, and the one that held Obama back from pursuing it — I think it could be. It represents one fewer way our world could descend into a nuclear war. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="JccuGb"&gt;Ultimately, a national security policy like our current one, which aims to confuse people about when we’ll use nuclear weapons, is one that might result in our using nuclear weapons when our adversaries didn’t mean to escalate that far and when there were other options on the table. Taking that possibility away is &lt;a href="https://lompocrecord.com/opinion/columnists/tyler-cowen-a-nuclear-first-strike-should-still-be-an/article_273698b9-36f4-5fc1-af17-7da30aeb8a08.html"&gt;not without downsides&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s also easy to underestimate the upsides — better odds that, in a shocking catastrophe of merely conventional scale, no one makes the mistake of turning the fight into a nuclear one.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="NPiq84"&gt;
            &lt;p id="5e9sLv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect-newsletter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the Future Perfect newsletter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; Twice a week, you’ll get a roundup of ideas and solutions for tackling our biggest challenges: improving public health, decreasing human and animal suffering, easing catastrophic risks, and — to put it simply — getting better at doing good.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="uioJIa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="DBQA3V"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2019/2/11/18216686/elizabeth-warren-ban-nuclear-weapons-no-first-use"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/2019/2/11/18216686/elizabeth-warren-ban-nuclear-weapons-no-first-use</id>
        <author>
            <name>Kelsey Piper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T14:20:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T14:20:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez’s rocky rollout of the Green New Deal, explained</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-NY) speaks as she and Sen. Ed Markey (D-MA) unveil the Green New Deal resolution." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gaBzlHG7EsdT0Mg7I8FA5rdXeAc=/0x0:4703x3527/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63035517/1128062794.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;A fact sheet from AOC’s office about the Green New Deal was wrong. It also highlighted the underlying tensions in the Democratic Party.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="wOHBlh"&gt;Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-NY) barely got to take a victory lap on her &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/2/7/18211709/green-new-deal-resolution-alexandria-ocasio-cortez-markey"&gt;Green New Deal resolution&lt;/a&gt; last week before a fight broke out over an accompanying set of talking points.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="HkxSgE"&gt;The conflict was rooted in what looks like a mistake on the part of Ocasio-Cortez’s office, which released a &lt;a href="https://assets.documentcloud.org/documents/5729035/Green-New-Deal-FAQ.pdf"&gt;fact sheet&lt;/a&gt; inconsistent with the actual legislative text of the Green New Deal resolution. In areas where the Green New Deal was purposefully vague to attract a broader base of Democratic support — such as renewable energy sources — Ocasio-Cortez’s fact sheet offered more specific and prescriptive priorities. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="UN1Xbt"&gt;One of the talking points included language promising economic security for even those “unwilling to work” — something that caught the ears of conservatives who claim entitlement programs stifle work productivity (there’s not much evidence to this effect). The &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-resolution/109/text"&gt;actual text&lt;/a&gt; states more broadly that the Green New Deal would “create millions of good, high-wage jobs and ensure prosperity and economic security for all people of the United States,” without mentioning anyone’s job status.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Jwxco8"&gt;The confusion opened up the Green New Deal to attacks from prominent conservative lawmakers and pundits like Tucker Carlson, Laura Ingraham, and others, who used the talking points as fodder to call the proposal idiotic and impractical. It also left both Ocasio-Cortez’s advisers and supporting Democrats flatfooted on live television, forcing them to answer for text they either didn’t know existed or couldn’t support. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="OoyzFp"&gt;Rep. Ed Markey (D-MA), one of the co-sponsors of the Green New Deal, told reporters, “Um ... I’m familiar with the fact sheet. But again, it’s separate from the resolution, all right? The resolution is really what the document is that I was speaking to today, as was Sen. Wyden and Sen. Merkley and all of the House members that were here. That’s the key document. That’s what you should focus on. Focus on the resolution.” His comments were an indication that some of the more moderate Democrats who have signed on to the Green New Deal may have been caught off guard by the language in Ocasio-Cortez’s talking points.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="A44wo1"&gt;Ocasio-Cortez’s office tried to smooth over the controversy by claiming the fact sheet was both an unfinished and old draft. They also raised&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;concerns about “doctored” documents about the Green New Deal being circulated by Republicans. Rather than slowing attacks, these claims have only fed the conservative outrage.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="qGBCZT"&gt;The Green New Deal is undoubtedly one of the most ambitious and progressive proposals to combat climate change and address economic inequality. The official legislative text includes several contentious proposals like Medicare-for-all and a jobs guarantee, as well as a commitment to seriously address climate change in a variety of ways, from improving construction work to investing in high speed rail. But at its core, it is still a compromise between left-wing activists and more mainstream Democrats, who are eager to work with the rising stars in the Democratic Party.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="f4IbkR"&gt;This flub with Ocasio-Cortez’s talking points puts that partnership off to a rocky start.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="6weME9"&gt;Republicans are using the fact sheet to delegitimize the Green New Deal&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="VMIM5A"&gt;The Green New Deal was never going to gain conservative support; it is, at its core, a progressive mission statement for tackling the big problems around climate change and expanding the social safety net. For this reason, the actual resolution’s legislative text has come under criticism in its own right. But the fact sheet opened up the Green New Deal to ridicule that could have been warded off.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="D5BPE3"&gt;It said things like the carbon emission goals were set at net zero in 10 years instead of at zero “because we aren’t sure that we’ll be able to fully get rid of farting cows and airplanes that fast” — a point that has since been mocked relentlessly. Even Sen. Ben Sasse (R-NE) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/senatorshoshana/status/1094778920103223296"&gt;temporarily changed his Twitter&lt;/a&gt; biography to “defender of cow’s right to fart.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="RrSlZD"&gt;The talking points also alarmed entitlement-wary Republicans with the suggestion that people “unwilling to work” could get benefits. For those who have seen Republicans’ &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/4/10/17221292/trump-welfare-executive-order-work-requirements"&gt;attempts to tie work requirements to everything from food stamps to health care&lt;/a&gt;, this should come as no surprise. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Po8Es7"&gt;Matt Whitlock, a senior adviser to the National Republican Senate Committee — the official campaign arm for Senate Republicans — &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mattdizwhitlock/status/1093887313585819649"&gt;called the document &lt;/a&gt;“utterly nonsensical.” Conservative pundit Ben Shapiro &lt;a href="https://www.dailywire.com/news/43194/aocs-green-new-deal-proposal-one-stupidest-ben-shapiro"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; that his “two-year-old son could come up with a better, more realistic proposal than this one. It’s not actually much of a competition.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="YOdqEk"&gt;The attacks escalated when Robert Hockett, a Cornell University professor, and outside adviser to Ocasio-Cortez, went on Tucker Carlson’s show to defend the Green New Deal, appearing wholly unaware of the fact sheet released by her office. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="9X6xTe"&gt;Carlson asked Hockett: “Why would we ever pay people who are ‘unwilling to work’?”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="mRo4b7"&gt;Hockett responded: “Uh, we never would, right? And AOC has never said anything like that, right?” going on to say the document Carlson was pulling from was “doctored,” and being circulated by Republicans — only to realize later it was real and from Ocasio-Cortez’s office.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="7fiuub"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.2493%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0qyx6eDkrmw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="hIg08S"&gt;Hockett’s comments started a second conservative media cycle about an Ocasio-Cortez surrogate supposedly lying on live television. The backlash prompted Ocasio-Cortez’s office to remove the “frequently asked questions” page from the representative’s website, and amend the fact sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="1sX37k"&gt;Ocasio Cortez’s staff doesn’t have a clear explanation for what happened&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="70cRFk"&gt;There hasn’t been a lot of clarity on exactly how this fact sheet got &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/daveweigel/status/1094344528864206850"&gt;sent out to numerous media organizations&lt;/a&gt; at the same time as the final Green New Deal resolution. Ocasio-Cortez’s office has said there is a fact sheet that was intentionally doctored, and also that an unfinished draft got sent out and posted on their website before it was ready for prime time.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="K0Hw4b"&gt;“There are multiple doctored GND resolutions and FAQs floating around,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AOC/status/1094331348813340672"&gt;Ocasio-Cortez tweeted this weekend&lt;/a&gt;. “There was also a draft version that got uploaded + taken down. There’s also draft versions floating out there.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="KnYgNG"&gt;But for the most part, Ocasio-Cortez’s office has backed away from Hockett’s assertion that the fact sheet was doctored and sent out by Republicans, saying that it was a mistake. In a string of Saturday tweets, Chakrabarti provided more clarity about the rollout of the Green New Deal and what went wrong with the fact sheet release.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="5iWXlH"&gt;“We did this in collaboration with a bunch of groups and offices over the course of the last month,” Chakrabarti tweeted on Saturday. “As part of that process, there were multiple iterations, brainstorming docs, FAQs, etc. that we shared. Some of these early drafts got leaked.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="Dr6byr"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;There separately IS a doctored FAQ floating around. And an early draft of a FAQ that was clearly unfinished and that doesn’t represent the GND resolution got published to the website by mistake (idea was to wait for launch, monitor q's, and rewrite that FAQ before publishing).&lt;/p&gt;— Saikat Chakrabarti (@saikatc) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/saikatc/status/1094263752806055936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 9, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="PAvRp2"&gt;Per Chakrabarti’s account, this fact sheet got “leaked” before it was ready; a statement that doesn’t quite match up with the accounts of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/daveweigel/status/1094344528864206850"&gt;multiple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/titonka/status/1095017535307763729"&gt;news organizations&lt;/a&gt; who say Ocasio-Cortez’s office sent them the fact sheet along with the final resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="YxdiyI"&gt;Additional confusion came when Chakrabarti and Ocasio-Cortez both alluded to a separate  “doctored” fact sheet. The Congress member’s staff hasn’t provided a lot of information around who wrote the talking points — and how much input outside groups had on the document that was released. Her office has not responded to a list of questions from Vox as of publication time. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="kSMauD"&gt;“There separately IS a doctored FAQ floating around,” Chakrabarti tweeted. “And an early draft of a FAQ that was clearly unfinished and that doesn’t represent the GND resolution go published to the website by mistake (idea was to wait for launch, monitor questions and rewrite that FAQ before publishing).”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="U4OSo0"&gt;But one thing is clear; the rollout has put Green New Deal supporters &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/2/7/18203910/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-green-new-deal-2020"&gt;including 2020 candidates&lt;/a&gt; in an uncomfortable position, having to answer questions about whether they’d support things that were never supposed to see the light of day. No matter the circumstances, a messy rollout could complicate support for the resolution in Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="OlR5t3"&gt;What’s in the actual Green New Deal represents a compromise with mainstream Democrats&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="lLA01L"&gt;The Green New Deal is Ocasio-Cortez’s signature issue since she became a member of Congress. The progressive firebrand from New York first made headlines attending a sit-in in House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s office with climate activists before she was even sworn in.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="wzCi9J"&gt;It is certainly a bold vision for how to deal with climate change, but the resolution’s official legislative text is also a compromise; it’s a version of the proposal that its writers believe can draw in more mainstream Democrats in addition to more left-wing activists. The very fact that Ocasio-Cortez is partnering with Markey says something; Markey was one of the authors of the 2009 cap-and-trade bill that passed the House and failed the Senate.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="6IpDRE"&gt;This is best exemplified by a discrepancy over renewable energy sources between the Green New Deal resolution and the fact sheet. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="W7P3lu"&gt;The appeal of the Green New Deal is in part how vague it is. Right now, the Green New Deal is a broad mission statement that doesn’t outline what specific renewables backers will sign onto — or how much everything will cost. The resolution itself is careful not to pick sides; it’s not choosing certain kinds of renewable energy over others, and it’s not calling for complete elimination of fossil fuels. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="F4yJm0"&gt;The fact sheet, on the other hand, clearly was picking sides. For instance, it made clear nuclear power would not be part of the climate solution, saying the Green New Deal plan “makes new fossil fuel infrastructure or nuclear plants unnecessary.” It panned carbon capture, utilization, and storage technology, and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/2/7/18215571/nancy-pelosi-green-new-deal-alexandria-ocasio-cortez"&gt;Markey’s 2009 cap-and-trade bill&lt;/a&gt;, framing cap and trade as a “tiny part” of the overall plan, and saying “cap and trade assumes the existing market will solve the problem for us, and that’s simply not true.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="7BnIib"&gt;That left Markey in a tough position on Thursday, trying to explain that the resolution was making no individual recommendations for how to get off fossil fuels as reporters lobbed questions about how the US could do this without nuclear power. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ODchLV"&gt;“There’s no individual prescriptions in the resolution, which is why we think we will be able to get a broad base of support, and then we’ll let the debates begin on the individual solutions,” Markey said gruffly. “We’ve drafted it in a way that can get the support of progressives and moderates inside our caucus.”&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/2/11/18220163/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-green-new-deal-faq-tucker-carlson"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/2/11/18220163/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-green-new-deal-faq-tucker-carlson</id>
        <author>
            <name>Tara Golshan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T13:55:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T13:55:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>Vaping gone viral: the astonishing surge in teens’ e-cigarette use</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="Juul pods pack as much nicotine as one to two packs of cigarettes. Juul also contains three times the nicotine levels permitted in the European Union, which is why Juul can’t be sold there." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jV3IMdjfe_3b4CRxdbgsQaj3EOk=/91x0:2758x2000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/62701468/1032883954.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;Youth use of e-cigarettes is rising at the fastest-recorded rate for any substance.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="GvUngi"&gt;Vaping has exploded in popularity in recent years — but not among the people it was intended for. Rather than adults trying to quit smoking, young people who’ve never picked up a cigarette are now vaping in record numbers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="S532gK"&gt;According to a new &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/vitalsigns/"&gt;Vital Signs report&lt;/a&gt;, published by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in 2018, some 4.9 million high school and middle school students used tobacco in the last 30 days, an increase from 3.6 million in 2017. E-cigarettes were the most popular tobacco product among the children and adolescents. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="traupe"&gt;The report follows a late 2018 &lt;a href="http://monitoringthefuture.org/pressreleases/18drugpr.pdf"&gt;National Institutes of Health survey&lt;/a&gt;, which tracked substance use among American adolescents. It found the number of high school seniors who say they vaped nicotine in the past 30 days doubled since 2017 — from 11 percent to nearly 21 percent. That was the largest increase ever recorded in any substance in the survey’s 43-year history. And it meant a quarter of 12th-grade students are now using, at least occasionally, a nicotine device that’s so new we have no idea what the long-term &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/6/26/8832337/e-cigarette-health-fda-smoking-safety"&gt;health impact&lt;/a&gt; of using it will be. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="BTx5s4"&gt;Young people’s extraordinarily rapid uptake of nicotine-delivery devices is one of the reasons Food and Drug Administration director Scott Gottlieb called for stronger regulations Monday. “Based on a growing body of evidence, I fear the youth trends will continue in 2019, forcing us to make some tough decisions about the regulatory status of e-cigarettes,” he said in a statement. “The signs that we’re seeing are not encouraging.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="RHQjhl"&gt;The reason for the concern: Nicotine is a highly addictive substance and can cause immediate &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/1/23/16923070/nas-report-e-cigarettes-health-risks"&gt;harmful side effects&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4560573/"&gt;young people’s developing brains&lt;/a&gt; and bodies. There’s some evidence that nicotine exposure may prime the developing brain to become more sensitive to substance use disorders later. Trying to quit nicotine can lead to serious withdrawal symptoms, including nervousness, restlessness, anxiety, sleepiness, and fatigue. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="xqkCQr"&gt;There’s also &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/1/23/16923070/nas-report-e-cigarettes-health-risks"&gt;strong evidence of a potential long-term impact: that vaping may encourage&lt;/a&gt; kids to smoke. “After years of progress in reducing youth cigarette smoking, today’s report shows ... a stall in progress in reducing youth cigarette use and possibly even an uptick among high school students,” Matthew Myers, president of the Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids, said in a statement. (That’s because the high school smoking rate went from 7.6 percent in 2017 to 8.1 percent in 2018.) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="FT0AC1"&gt;“The kids using e-cigarettes are children who rejected conventional cigarettes, but don’t see the same stigma associated with the use of e-cigarettes,” Gottlieb added. “But now, having become exposed to nicotine through e-cigs, they will be more likely to smoke.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="EVJk7R"&gt;This may be only the beginning. Like the cigarette industry before it, vaping companies have found effective ways to market their wares to young people. The way they design and pitch their products packs a dual punch: They are both high-tech and highly addicting. That’s left regulators scrambling to keep up, and a big question mark about what vaping nicotine might mean for the health outcomes of this new generation.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="nvd39e"&gt;The way nicotine is marketed has changed &lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;div id="0XVJim"&gt;
            &lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="How Juul made nicotine go viral|39773" data-volume-uuid="562982b22" data-volume-id="39773" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-960" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="eD4nff"&gt;To understand the surge in vaping among youth, you need to understand &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/5/1/17286638/juul-vaping-e-cigarette"&gt;Juul&lt;/a&gt;, the popular — and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/27/science/juul-vaping-teen-marketing.html"&gt;controversial&lt;/a&gt; — e-cigarette that many argue helped vaping nicotine go viral. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="2OHMHf"&gt;The company’s &lt;a href="https://www.juul.com/mission-values"&gt;stated mission&lt;/a&gt; is “improving the lives of the world’s one billion adult smokers.” Created by two former smokers and Stanford design graduates (one of whom also worked as a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1516588&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fin%2Fabowen%2F"&gt;design engineer at Apple&lt;/a&gt;), the duo wanted to make a device that looked sleek and attractive:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="xMIXC1"&gt;When they could find no attractive alternative to cigarettes, [James Monsees and Adam Bowen] recognized a groundbreaking opportunity to apply industrial design to the smoking industry, which had not materially evolved in over one hundred years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p id="gVeTD2"&gt;So they designed an e-cigarette that could easily be mistaken for a USB flash drive and can fit in the palm of the hand.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="xIrBjY"&gt;But here’s the thing: Not only is the device slick, but its pods pack as much nicotine as one to two packs of cigarettes. Juul also contains three times the nicotine levels permitted in the European Union, which is why Juul can’t be sold there.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="yzRSw4"&gt;So the appeal of Juul — with its high-tech design — is “compounded by its addictiveness,” said &lt;a href="http://publichealth.gsu.edu/profile/michaeleriksen/"&gt;Michael Eriksen&lt;/a&gt;, dean of the school of public health at Georgia State University and a former director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s Office on Smoking and Health, “and I think that explains the rapidity of the uptake.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="A019Iz"&gt;In 2017, the US market &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/24/health/fda-e-cigarettes-minors-juul.html"&gt;expanded by 40 percent&lt;/a&gt; to $1.16 billion, with a lot of that growth driven by Juul.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="hvLuOY"&gt;As of March, Juul made up more than half of all e-cigarette retail market sales in the US, &lt;a href="http://www.publichealthlawcenter.org/sites/default/files/JUUL-Webinar-Slides-Apr262018.pdf"&gt;according to Nielsen data&lt;/a&gt;. Considering it has only been on the market since 2015 and there are &lt;a href="http://tobaccocontrol.bmj.com/content/23/suppl_3/iii3"&gt;hundreds of other devices&lt;/a&gt; available to consumers, Juul’s market share is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="JnG9Ak"&gt;Marketing nicotine expressly to youth isn’t new. In the 1990s, when Eriksen was an expert witness for the Federal Trade Commission’s crackdown on Big Tobacco’s marketing of cigarettes to youth, he explained that tobacco companies like Reynold’s and Marlboro targeted their ads at young people. “They were consolidating around the imagery of the cowboy, [signaling] independence,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="CQW4wO"&gt;But what’s new, said Eriksen, is “this combination of innovation, social media spread, and the fact that it’s unfortunately addicting at the same time.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="XD0oyH"&gt;A recent analysis of &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/1/25/18194953/vape-juul-e-cigarette-marketing"&gt;Juul’s early ads, out of Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, showed Juul employed social media influencers and ads that deliberately targeted youth. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="e3A6N4"&gt;An unscientific survey of high schoolers and teachers confirmed Juul’s virality. “I don’t recall any fad, legal or illegal, catching on in this way,” Meg Kenny, the assistant head of school at Burr and Burton Academy in Manchester, Vermont, who has worked in education for 20 years, told &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/5/1/17286638/juul-vaping-e-cigarette"&gt;Vox in April&lt;/a&gt;. Students at her school were Juuling in bathrooms, in class, and on the bus. Because it’s against the school’s rules, they were also hiding the devices in ceiling tiles and in their bras and underwear.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="fw44eb"&gt;Regulators are scrambling to keep up &lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="p2wOmP"&gt;The surge of teen vaping has left &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/18/health/vaping-nicotine-teenagers.html"&gt;addiction specialists wondering how to best help young people who want to quit&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also left health regulators scrambling and sluggish in their response to the trend. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="y5B3dw"&gt;Here’s the conundrum: It’s true that e-cigarettes do hold potential to help adult smokers move on to a less deadly alternative. That’s why they’re widely viewed as potential harm-reduction tools. But regulators have been struggling with how to strike a balance between curbing the uptake of e-cigarettes in minors while also helping smokers quit. In the meantime, youth vaping exploded. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="p2LAYe"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/7/28/16055978/fda-cigarettes-nicotine"&gt;July 2017&lt;/a&gt;, the FDA delayed the compliance deadline for the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/28/health/electronic-cigarette-tobacco-nicotine-fda.html"&gt;regulation of e-cigarette products&lt;/a&gt; to 2022. This gave the industry five more years to file public health applications that show that their products are safe alternatives to conventional cigarettes and that they weren’t unduly targeting minors.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="m2A9hC"&gt;Gottlieb positioned the delay as a way to give manufacturers time to get in step with the new laws while ensuring smokers had access to cigarette alternatives that could save their lives. But some health advocates viewed it another way: as a giveaway for the vaping industry, and a chance for e-cigarette makers to further expand their market share among kids at a time when e-cigarette use by teens has &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/4/16/8433415/e-cigarette-use-teens-2014"&gt;eclipsed conventional cigarette use&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="mDJ9vT"&gt;It turns out those advocates may have been right. “I don’t want anyone to think I’m against the harm-reduction potential of these devices for adults,” Surgeon General Jerome Adams said on &lt;a href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=49de65a615a71dd483d6414aa0fd2258fbb61b71af4599d7dff70920d0b59826af407f8c748c8ecbbdc91b1c8502d218"&gt;Politico’s &lt;em&gt;Pulse Check&lt;/em&gt; podcast&lt;/a&gt; in December, explaining his call for new regulations that might curb youth vaping, including taxes and indoor vaping bans. “But 3 percent of adults are using these devices — [and] 20 percent of high schoolers are using these devices.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="JF79Ys"&gt;More recently, the FDA has been taking action against Juul and teen e-cigarette use — but has stopped short of changing the compliance deadline. In April, the FDA &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/UCM605432.htm?utm_source=Eloqua&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_term=stratcomms&amp;amp;utm_content=link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=CTP%20News%26Connect%26SOS%3A%20Juul%20Actions%20%28New%29%20-%2042418"&gt;took the unusual step&lt;/a&gt; of demanding Juul Labs submit documents about its marketing and research and what it knows about Juul use among young people. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="GoXIqn"&gt;In May, the agency followed up by &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm607935.htm"&gt;sending requests for information to four other e-cigarette makers&lt;/a&gt; that also appear to be marketing to young people.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="qzKqIy"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/11/14/18088468/juul-e-cigarette-menthol-fda-ban"&gt;November&lt;/a&gt;, the agency said it would restrict the sales of flavored e-cigarettes in stores and online — though it wouldn’t outright ban vape flavors in brick-and-mortar retailers, a move that was widely anticipated after &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/fda-plans-to-sharply-restrict-sales-of-flavored-e-cigarettes-1541731110"&gt;leaked reports&lt;/a&gt; from the FDA ahead of the news.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Zbrj4H"&gt;And some wish the FDA would go further. “The mass marketing of cigarettes, a highly sophisticated, addictive, and defective nicotine delivery device that kills over 7 million people globally every year, is an abuse of corporate power and a human rights violation,” said Laurent Huber, Executive Director of ASH, an anti-tobacco nonprofit, in November. “Banning menthol is a step in the right direction, but it is time to go one step further and phase cigarettes out of the market to prevent millions of unnecessary deaths.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="FWwb9o"&gt;I checked back with Meg Kenny, the assistant head of school at Burr and Burton Academy in Vermont, about Juuling on her campus. She says it appears to have cooled off this winter. While 95 percent of disciplinary infractions at the school were connected to Juul last fall and spring, 50 percent were this fall. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="oOzKSf"&gt;Maybe the awareness and crackdowns are having an impact. Or maybe the Juulers have moved on to cigarettes or have gotten better at hiding the habit. By next year’s youth tobacco surveys, we’ll have a preliminary answer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="QU9rLa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more on Juul and e-cigarettes, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/5/1/17286638/juul-vaping-e-cigarette"&gt;&lt;em&gt;read our explainer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, listen to the May 3, 2018, episode of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://art19.com/shows/today-explained/episodes/3cfdf464-8619-4ebe-a343-42458870cb77"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today, Explained&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and watch &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/8/10/17675836/juul-design-viral"&gt;&lt;em&gt;our Vox video here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="LsYhLe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="jLxf7e"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="4Olxr5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="kLQlfp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="dfJKoG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="yylaiH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="FCQh8N"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="dMBHOw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="pkHHFw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/12/18/18144951/juul-vaping-e-cigarettes"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/12/18/18144951/juul-vaping-e-cigarettes</id>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Belluz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T13:38:52-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T13:38:52-05:00</updated>
        <title>The controversy over Ilhan Omar and AIPAC money, explained</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HDj-GqaZfFszGvdowa3Cd2Ta_h4=/667x0:6000x4000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63034601/1124584283.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;It’s only somewhat about the Benjamins. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="EVYgXb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/1/28/18185633/house-republican-agenda-2020"&gt;House Republicans don’t have a policy agenda&lt;/a&gt; that they’re planning to wield to win back the House from Nancy Pelosi and the Democrats, but they do have a new favored wedge issue: Israel. Republicans, led by Rep. Kevin McCarthy, are accusing two new Muslim members of Congress, who’ve made strident criticisms of Israel, of anti-Semitism.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="KJHbNS"&gt;The specifics of the controversy of the moment (&lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2019/02/10/ilhan-omar-israel-aipac-money-1163631"&gt;“Omar ignites new anti-Semitism controversy with comments on AIPAC,”&lt;/a&gt; according to Politico) relate to some moderately ill-advised tweets Rep. Ilhan Omar (D-MN) fired off Sunday night. But the tweets themselves only arose in the larger context of what was &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; a push from Republican leaders to label Omar and  Rep. Rashida Tlaib (D-MI) as anti-Semitic over their view on Israel policy. That’s not a novel tactic to anyone familiar with the discourse around this subject, but it’s taken on a new urgency in the current Congress for two parallel reasons. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ELlKll"&gt;First, under the leadership of Benjamin Netanyahu, the government of Israel has become increasingly comfortable with the concept of Israel being used as a partisan wedge issue — something Israeli leaders traditionally felt would undermine Israel’s political support in the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="P2HQBC"&gt;Second, as part of a larger resurgence of left-wing politics in the United States, a minority of Democrats are becoming increasingly comfortable with overt hostility to the Israeli government — and at least &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; establishment Democrats, stung by Netanyahu’s conduct during President Obama’s eight years in office, are prepared to back them. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="sXvVP0"&gt;Nonetheless, the issue of Israel remains deeply — indeed, almost uniquely — divisive in the Democratic Party. After about twelve hours of controversy, Omar’s remarks led to a remarkable joint rebuke from the entire House Democratic leadership team calling them “deeply offended.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
            &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CXqNUDlFueC3uvrRizpyT892ofQ=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13752266/Screen_Shot_2019_02_11_at_1.35.56_PM.png"&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;p id="hlBnRd"&gt;Omar, in turn, apologized for the phrasing of her tweet while standing behind the substantive criticism of AIPAC’s policy agenda. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="CO9MV3"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Listening and learning, but standing strong    &lt;a href="https://t.co/7TSroSf8h1"&gt;pic.twitter.com/7TSroSf8h1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ilhan Omar (@IlhanMN) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IlhanMN/status/1095046561254567937?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="hMVJr5"&gt;Meanwhile, the pro-Israel establishment in the American Jewish community remains determined to flex considerable financial muscle in favor of its preferred policy approach while simultaneously accusing those like Omar who draw attention to this fact of trafficking in anti-Semitic stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="toBVGo"&gt;Ilhan Omar’s Sunday night twitter controversy&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="Gn21Gr"&gt;It all began, as so many things do these days, with public figures being Extremely Online during non-working hours. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ssMBgY"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/1/16/18183799/gop-steve-king-conservatism-racism-language-politics"&gt;years of tolerating Iowa Rep. Steve King’s increasingly overt racism&lt;/a&gt;, McCarthy took action against him early this year by stripping him of his committee assignments. Then on Sunday, &lt;a href="https://www.haaretz.com/world-news/kevin-mccarthy-promises-action-against-ilhan-omar-and-rashida-tlaib-1.6917751"&gt;Ron Kampeas of the JTA news service reported that McCarthy&lt;/a&gt; was preparing to challenge Democrats to take similar action against Omar and Tlaib, arguing, according to Kampeas, that “statements by freshmen Democrats Rashida Tlaib of Michigan and Ilhan Omar of Minnesota were equal to King’s and ‘more so.’”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="J6QoOp"&gt;It wasn’t clear from Kampeas’s report which statements he had in mind, but in the larger context of the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/1/9/18172826/bds-law-israel-boycott-states-explained"&gt;GOP push for laws that would punish people for boycotting Israel&lt;/a&gt;, it seems like he was trying to say that Omar and Tlaib supporting the Boycott, Divestment, and Sanctions (BDS) movement was worthy of punishment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="jFqRBV"&gt;That led Glenn Greenwald, a prominent journalist and critic of both Israel and BDS laws, to send a tweet. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="JpNp2q"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;GOP Leader Kevin McCarthy threatens punishment for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IlhanMN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@IlhanMN&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RashidaTlaib?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@RashidaTlaib&lt;/a&gt; over their criticisms of Israel. It's stunning how much time US political leaders spend defending a foreign nation even if it means attacking free speech rights of Americans &lt;a href="https://t.co/It1fGm1b70"&gt;https://t.co/It1fGm1b70&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Glenn Greenwald (@ggreenwald) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ggreenwald/status/1094727576013193216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="TLhPUc"&gt;Then Omar followed up on Greenwald by saying that McCarthy’s approach to this issue was &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ad6peGZqqAA"&gt;“all about the Benjamins baby”&lt;/a&gt; (i.e., motivated by money). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="Qn1R9C"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It's all about the Benjamins baby   &lt;a href="https://t.co/KatcXJnZLV"&gt;https://t.co/KatcXJnZLV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ilhan Omar (@IlhanMN) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IlhanMN/status/1094747501578633216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="3DWuHL"&gt;Offered an opportunity to clarify by Batya Ungar-Sargon, the opinion editor for the Forward, Omar instead upped the ante to say clearly that she believes the American Israel Public Affairs Committee is paying American politicians to be pro-Israel. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="doLAzA"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="ca" dir="ltr"&gt;AIPAC! &lt;a href="https://t.co/UdzaFUEfrh"&gt;https://t.co/UdzaFUEfrh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ilhan Omar (@IlhanMN) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IlhanMN/status/1094761790595088384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="2UZHLk"&gt;This is a sensitive subject for Jewish Americans with a wide range of views about Israel and US foreign policy, and by responding in this way to McCarthy’s provocations, Omar essentially gave McCarthy the pretext he’d previously lacked to analogize her to King. Omar’s fellow first-term Democrat Rep. Max Rose (D-NY) swiftly slammed her remarks as &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/house/429358-dem-lawmaker-omars-statements-deeply-hurtful-to-jews"&gt;“deeply hurtful to Jews,”&lt;/a&gt; TPM’s Josh Marshall deemed it a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/joshtpm/status/1094767140366888962"&gt;“very unfortunate tweet,”&lt;/a&gt; and even &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/ilhan-omar-aipac-tweet-condemnation-including-from-chelsea-clinton"&gt;Chelsea Clinton joined the pile-on&lt;/a&gt;, which prompted a whole other series of counterattacks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="xd1qLS"&gt;Lest you think any of this is happening in good faith, recall that McCarthy himself in October was accusing three Jewish Democrats of trying to “buy” the 2018 midterms. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="orz3SI"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Majority Leader Kevin McCarthy posted this tweet AFTER a bomb was sent to Soros' house. Up until a couple of minutes ago it was pinned to the top of his profile. &lt;a href="https://t.co/FEeKoPolHL"&gt;pic.twitter.com/FEeKoPolHL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Judd Legum (@JuddLegum) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JuddLegum/status/1055170806949523458?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 24, 2018&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="3ITx5K"&gt;Nonetheless, whether or not one takes McCarthy’s complaints seriously, he has correctly identified a potentially explosive issue that is very well-calibrated to the specific goal of getting Democrats to fight with each other about a topic most Americans probably don’t care very much about. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="nQLbC8"&gt;It’s only partially about the Benjamins&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="ztQr42"&gt;The notion that congressional support for Israel is literally &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; about the Benjamins is clearly false, and Omar could have saved herself some grief by acknowledging as much in response to Ungar-Sargon’s initial inquiry. There are, pretty obviously, major questions of ethnic and religious identity in play — not just among American Jews but also with the incredible influence of Christian Zionism in American politics and, conversely, the not-coincidental reality that Omar and Tlaib, who are both Muslim, have strong feelings on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="F7btZw"&gt;That said, while it’s true that to suggest a cabal of Jewish moneymen control Congress from behind the scenes via their perfidious financial influence certainly does traffic in anti-Semitic stereotypes, it’s also clearly true that pro-Israel forces’ financial clout makes a difference in American politics. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ltGNBq"&gt;Don’t take my word for it — &lt;a href="https://www.aipac.org/act/congressional-club"&gt;ask AIPAC&lt;/a&gt;, which says that “the United States Congress has provided Israel with the strongest support of any institution in the world” and tells its members that “involvement in the political process is a tangible way of showing friends of Israel that you care about who serves in Congress.” It also specifically defines this in terms of being sufficiently generous with your campaign contributions to qualify as a member of AIPAC’s Congressional Club. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
            &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kCyrMc7w-eS8SwwDeVnqN9MlZ5I=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13751704/Screen_Shot_2019_02_11_at_10.08.53_AM.png"&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;p id="EE84gU"&gt;Beyond its involvement in encouraging campaign contributions, AIPAC also spends a lot of money on lobbying. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="l4uw8K"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/lobby/indusclient.php?id=Q05&amp;amp;year=2018"&gt;$3.5 million AIPAC spent lobbying in 2018&lt;/a&gt; is trivial compared to what business groups spend (the National Association of Realtors took the cake with $543 million in spending and mostly lost the argument over the home mortgage tax deduction anyway), but very large relative to the world of foreign policy. The No. 2 foreign policy donor, UNICEF USA, spent just $744,000, and its activities are orthogonal to AIPAC’s interests anyway. The largest group lobbying on the other side of AIPAC, J Street, not only spent less than 10 percent of AIPAC’s lobbying budget, it actually got outspent by a second, smaller hawkish Israel policy group, the &lt;a href="https://iacforaction.org"&gt;Israeli-American Coalition for Action&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="kqjPQd"&gt;Last but by no means least, AIPAC spends on less formal means of influence-peddling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="hH7gB4"&gt;Their annual trips to Israel for members of Congress are perennially the most popular form of foreign congressional travel, in no small part because the accommodations are rather lavish. &lt;a href="https://t.co/1O6jLRHrvu?amp=1"&gt;As Rachael Bade and Amanda Becker have reported&lt;/a&gt;, AIPAC spends around $10,000 per guest on business-class airfare and luxury accommodations. Members are allowed to bring spouses and other family guests on the trips, and members frequently go multiple times. &lt;a href="https://forward.com/news/israel/161528/laughs-aside-junkets-raise-serious-issues/?p=all&amp;amp;p=all"&gt;Comparable junkets for journalists&lt;/a&gt; are also available.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="pJqgJr"&gt;To view this as the primary driver of a &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2014/7/24/5929705/us-israel-friends"&gt;foreign policy relationship that has roots in Cold War strategy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.jta.org/2018/07/24/politics/christian-zionist-confab-draws-5000-celebrates-trump-era-us-israel-relations"&gt;substantial links to evangelical eschatology&lt;/a&gt; is mistaken. But there’s also something a little willfully naive about the counter-assertion that money is irrelevant. Haim Saban, a major Democratic Party donor, for example, has in the past described himself as &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1516588&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fmagazine%2F2010%2F05%2F10%2Fthe-influencer%23ixzz0mtTMEqPs" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“a one-issue guy, and my issue is Israel.”&lt;/a&gt; That gives many rank-and-file Democrats who don’t particularly care about foreign policy (a good description of most members of Congress) good reason to adopt a pro-Israel line and enjoy the benefits rather than rocking the boat. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="IRfQ75"&gt;Republicans want a wedge; Omar gave them a sledgehammer&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="SlaKR1"&gt;The larger context for this controversy, however, is not the strength of the pro-Israel lobby but its weakness. The concurrent administrations of Obama in the United States and Netanyahu in Israel led to a serious deterioration of the relationship between Democrats and pro-Israel organizations. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="q71AHA"&gt;On a policy level, that was largely about Iran, where Israel stridently opposed Obama’s nuclear deal but congressional Democrats mostly chose partisanship and ideology over AIPAC’s preferences. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Mg5F7A"&gt;On a political level, that was about Netanyahu’s eagerness to break with precedent and allow Israel to be used as a partisan wedge issue — all but openly campaigning on behalf of Mitt Romney and John Boehner against Obama and congressional Democrats — even while aware that this risked a backlash from Democrats in Congress. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Kp0Ald"&gt;In the Trump era, the United States has tilted further than ever in a pro-Israel direction (moving the US Embassy to Jerusalem even without a diplomatic agreement with the Palestinians about the status of the city), while Democrats have grown stronger in their criticisms of anti-Iranian activities by Saudi Arabia and the UAE that Israel supports. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Yvgbex"&gt;Bernie Sanders has played a leading role in much of this, continuing a &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/4/15/11437832/bernie-sanders-just-shattered-an-american-taboo-on-israel"&gt;trajectory of shattering taboos&lt;/a&gt; that he launched during his 2016 campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="v7POdp"&gt;But Sanders, who is Jewish, and whose policy team includes seasoned professionals with years of experience on the issue, manages to make his points in a thoughtful, politically effective way. Omar’s social media bomb-throwing, by contrast, is a gift to congressional Republicans who are eager to promote Democratic infighting. And there is now infighting aplenty, with other Democrats rushing to distance themselves from Omar while more left-wing writers and activists emphasize their agreement with the basic point that pro-Israel money matters. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="D6WOmj"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NADLER: “It is deeply disappointing and disturbing to hear Representative Ilhan Omar’s (MN) choice of words in her exchange with a journalist yesterday, wherein she appears to traffic in old anti-Semitic tropes about Jews and money."&lt;/p&gt;— Sam Stein (@samstein) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/samstein/status/1094981089486090240?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div id="j0vPgJ"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;For nearly two weeks, Rep. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IlhanMN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@IlhanMN&lt;/a&gt; has avoided meeting with me to discuss why anti-Semitic tropes like these are hurtful to so many Americans.  There is absolutely no place for this rhetoric in Congress -- or anywhere. &lt;a href="https://t.co/0arhEAVyXO"&gt;https://t.co/0arhEAVyXO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Rep Josh Gottheimer (@RepJoshG) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepJoshG/status/1094830756067753986?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div id="amGJ6t"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;accurately describing how the Israel lobby works is not anti-semitism &lt;a href="https://t.co/30M6rVmeJb"&gt;https://t.co/30M6rVmeJb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ashley Feinberg (@ashleyfeinberg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleyfeinberg/status/1094789464747134981?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="P6HiVA"&gt;The fundamental reality, however, is that this is an inherently difficult topic for Democrats. A large majority of Americans say they sympathize more with the Israeli side than the Palestinian side in the conflict, but &lt;a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/229199/americans-remain-staunchly-israel-corner.aspx"&gt;rank-and-file Democrats are split roughly 50-50&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
            &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ognYplc7RI9iYw05qa1z-_9Rvd4=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13751854/m41x8w6q1uytvnhhcexdxa.png"&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;p id="WDT4GU"&gt;That means that in order to be effective, people who want to challenge the pro-Israel consensus in politics need to be careful and strategic with their interventions — the opposite of tossing off inflammatory tweets on a Sunday evening with no strategy lined up. &lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2019/2/11/18220160/ilhan-omar-aipac-benjamins-kevin-mccarthy"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/2019/2/11/18220160/ilhan-omar-aipac-benjamins-kevin-mccarthy</id>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Yglesias</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T13:35:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T13:35:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>Denver teachers are striking for the first time in 25 years</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="Denver teachers, students, and community members picket outside South High School on February 11, 2019." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xbr2Xe8Plob4xeCHouLcu_3bIow=/275x0:4668x3295/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63035396/GettyImages_1097912614.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="wCtAa5"&gt;Denver’s public school teachers went on strike Monday, following the lead of teachers &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/4/13/17226654/teacher-strike-west-virginia-oklahoma-arizona-2018"&gt;across the country&lt;/a&gt; who have refused to go to work until they get a raise.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="QiZWQM"&gt;The walkout comes after more than 15 months of tense negotiations between the school district and the teachers union over the compensation system, which relies heavily on bonuses that fluctuate wildly from year to year.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="hcQEAi"&gt;Teachers say their salaries are too low for Denver’s high cost of living and aren’t keeping up with pay in neighboring districts. They also point out that the district has way more administrators than other districts of similar size, which eats into the school budget.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="CkHk2A"&gt;Denver officials &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DPSNewsNow/status/1094442332097777664"&gt;said they are listening&lt;/a&gt;, and that they’re willing to give teachers a raise but want to keep offering bonuses to teachers who work in high-poverty communities.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="oabJJA"&gt;“We’re disappointed that the [Denver Classroom Teachers Association] walked away from the table. We presented an updated proposal that responds to what we have heard from teachers, aligns to our values of equity and retention, honors the &lt;a href="https://www.dpsk12.org/wp-content/uploads/ProComp-Ballot-Language.pdf"&gt;ProComp ballot language&lt;/a&gt; and significantly increases the base pay for teachers,” the district &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DPSNewsNow/status/1094442332097777664"&gt;stated on Monday&lt;/a&gt;, after negotiations fell apart over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="PMZQ4t"&gt;City and state officials tried hard to keep teachers from going on strike. Colorado lawmakers &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/4/23/17270422/colorado-teachers-strike-jail-bill"&gt;threatened them&lt;/a&gt; with jail time. School administrators &lt;a href="https://www.denverpost.com/2019/02/06/jared-polis-denver-teachers-strike/"&gt;asked the governor&lt;/a&gt; to stop them. Neither effort worked, though, and more than 2,000 teachers are now picketing on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="M6Fq8h"&gt;“Now is our time,” Sonia Burns, a Denver high school social studies teacher, told me. “There is a movement around the country and we’ve gotten so much support from the community.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="b9zvEu"&gt;Unlike other districts where teachers went on strike, Denver officials have decided to keep the schools open during the stoppage, counting on administrators and substitute teachers to keep students on schedule. However, preschool classes were canceled Monday because they &lt;a href="https://www.denverpost.com/2019/02/11/denver-teachers-strike-monday/"&gt;couldn’t find enough licensed teachers &lt;/a&gt;to fill in.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="1yYhB8"&gt;Burns, who has been teaching in Denver for eight years, said teachers are nervous but determined. The school district has offered educators a 10 percent raise, but the Denver Classroom Teachers Association, a labor union representing about 5,700 educators, wants the district to &lt;a href="https://denverteachers.org/wp-content/uploads/2-9-DCTA-Proposal-6pm.pdf"&gt;overhaul the entire compensation system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="xPpR8C"&gt;Arbitrary bonuses and low pay&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="d3caRU"&gt;Teachers are most upset about Denver’s incentive pay system, which started more than a year ago. The district pays bonuses based on teacher performance, and to encourage teachers to work in high-poverty schools. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="A5Ed9g"&gt;But the union &lt;a href="https://denverteachers.org/the-100000-teacher-plan/"&gt;says the bonuses vary too much&lt;/a&gt; from year to year, creating financial instability for educators and their families. They also say it’s unclear how the district measures good performance and determines bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="nejIBr"&gt;Instead, teachers want the district to lower bonuses and increase their base salaries, and to give them salaries based on education and training, like most school districts do.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="q4KKfh"&gt;Colorado teachers are among the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/3/9/17100404/teacher-salary-underpaid-database"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lowest-paid in the country&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, earning an average of $46,155 in 2016 — ranking Colorado 46th in average teacher pay, according to the National Education Association. The state also spends about $2,500 less per student each year than the national average. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="ZKDf3B"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Marching in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Solidarity?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Solidarity&lt;/a&gt; with ⁦&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DenverTeachers?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DenverTeachers&lt;/a&gt;⁩ this morning. Incredible support from the community, chanting and honking and bringing supplies. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RedforEd?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#RedforEd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FairPayForTeachers?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#FairPayForTeachers&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ca8fOnIIRT"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ca8fOnIIRT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Rep. Emily Sirota (@EmilyForCO) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EmilyForCO/status/1094967775020240897?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="TLniu5"&gt;The Denver Classroom Teachers Association voted to authorize a strike in January with support from 93 percent of its members. At the time, the two sides were about $8 million apart in reaching an agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="QOGuzA"&gt;After authorizing a strike, the school district fought back. They asked Gov. Jared Polis to intervene, a legal move that delayed the strike as the state government weighed its options. But last week, the governor declined to intervene in the dispute, which could have further delayed a strike by up to 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="yhOLpx"&gt;That wasn’t the first attempt to keep teachers from going on strike, though. Far from it.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="3k7SFV"&gt;Republican lawmakers tried to make striking illegal&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="uqWvrr"&gt;In April, two Republican state legislators tried to shut down a potential teachers strike in Colorado with the threat of jail time.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="BSYuWp"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://leg.colorado.gov/sites/default/files/documents/2018A/bills/2018a_264_01.pdf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, introduced in the state Senate, prohibited districts from supporting a teachers strike and required schools to dock a teacher’s pay for each day they participate in a walkout. The teachers could also have faced up to six months in jail and a $500 daily fine if they violated a court order to stop striking.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="5EMRxr"&gt;The bill was a reaction to the teacher strikes sweeping red and purple states, including &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/4/3/17191082/oklahoma-teachers-protest-pay"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oklahoma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/3/3/17074824/west-virginia-teachers-strike-justice-union"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;West Virginia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/4/13/17234984/arizona-teacher-strike-redfored"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arizona&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/4/16/17242812/kentucky-governor-bevin-teachers-strike-child-assault"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kentucky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Thousands of teachers in Colorado had joined the grassroots movement, &lt;a href="https://www.denverpost.com/2018/04/16/colorado-teacher-walkout-rally/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;holding rallies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at the state capitol to demand a pay raise and more funding.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="OrMyk3"&gt;The bill failed. And now the teachers are on strike in Denver — for the first time in 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="XMHDT7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="iQlfKt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="mRV8Ks"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2019/2/11/18217268/denver-teachers-strike"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/2019/2/11/18217268/denver-teachers-strike</id>
        <author>
            <name>Alexia Fernández Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <published>2019-02-11T13:10:00-05:00</published>
        <updated>2019-02-11T13:10:00-05:00</updated>
        <title>Nearly all of the big dating apps are now owned by the same company</title>
        <content type="html">
            &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZQaUSmgvoYDOwjdSArMY7nMjvOc=/267x0:3734x2600/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/63034966/1074769034.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;



            &lt;p&gt;Tinder’s parent company has acquired “the relationship app” Hinge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="9aQX5o"&gt;Match Group, which operates dating apps like Tinder and OkCupid, completed its acquisition of the 7-year-old app Hinge on Thursday, following its purchase of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/2018/6/20/17485750/match-group-acquire-hinge-deal-online-dating"&gt;a majority stake&lt;/a&gt; in June 2018.  &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="2DE5Pe"&gt;For years, Hinge has positioned itself as the alternative to Tinder, a way to get away from the shallowness and disappointment of flipping through trading-card profiles in an endless carousel. The self-proclaimed “relationship app,” Hinge matched people based on their mutual friends, was supposedly “designed to be deleted,” and boasted love as its core company value — purposely decentralizing the gamification central to swiping apps but never quite going after the advanced matchmaking algorithm promises of Match.com or OkCupid. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="9ti1BA"&gt;But in essence, all dating apps sell you the same thing, which is access to people who might want to date you, and some tools for sifting through them. There is very little about the technology itself that makes one or the other more valuable, so buying a new dating app is almost literally just buying more customers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="6kN3J9"&gt;Right now, it looks like the near future will see every major dating app ending up in the same hands, just one of the many stories of industry consolidation we’re witnessing in what antitrust expert Tim Wu &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2018/11/8/18076440/facebook-monopoly-curse-of-bigness-tim-wu-interview"&gt;has called&lt;/a&gt; the second Gilded Age, which is maybe abstractly scary — but more tangibly so when you think about Facebook as the only company that could possibly stop it. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="BHr96m"&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="iJfE8Y"&gt;What is Hinge, and why would Match Group want it? &lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="MwkSsD"&gt;The dating app industry is a massively lucrative one, particularly now that app-makers have figured out how to monetize all of their individual features: Match’s &lt;a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/279430125/files/doc_presentations/MTCH-Q4-2018-Investor-Presentation.pdf"&gt;fourth-quarter earnings&lt;/a&gt; for 2018 showed that Tinder added 1.2 million new users last year, and that it brought in $805 million in revenue — more than double &lt;a href="https://www.recode.net/2018/8/8/17662746/tinder-revenue-match-group-q2-earnings"&gt;the year before&lt;/a&gt;. In total, Match Group brought in about $1.7 billion, a pretty big share of a growing pie. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/reuters/2019/02/06/technology/06reuters-match-group-results.html"&gt;Analysts estimate&lt;/a&gt; the global dating app market will be worth about $12 billion a year by 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ibbES5"&gt;The dating app empire owned by the umbrella company InterActiveCorp (IAC) was founded in 1995, with Match.com as its cornerstone. It also operates the study guide and college-rating company the Princeton Review, and &lt;a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/match-group-can-get-away-acquiring-25-dating-sites-counting-151306438.html"&gt;now owns&lt;/a&gt; upward of 45 dating-related businesses, including 25 acquisitions. Following its incorporation in 2009, it began aggressively courting acquisitions, including OkCupid in 2011, then Plenty of Fish in 2015 — four months before its initial public offering, at which it was valued at $2.9 billion. Its crown jewel is Tinder, which was developed by IAC’s internal incubator Hatch Labs and launched in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="F12EAM"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/BsWOjbiBcr5/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading" data-instgrm-version="12" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:16px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BsWOjbiBcr5/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div style="padding: 19% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"&gt;&lt;svg width="50px" height="50px" viewbox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"&gt;&lt;g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div style="padding-top: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"&gt;
            &lt;div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div style="margin-left: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div style="margin-left: auto;"&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BsWOjbiBcr5/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank"&gt;Adiós! Ciao! Arrivederci! Deuces! ✌️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/hinge/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;" target="_blank"&gt; Hinge&lt;/a&gt; (@hinge) on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2019-01-07T20:48:03+00:00"&gt;Jan 7, 2019 at 12:48pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="hD6MhE"&gt;Hinge, on the other hand, almost failed at launch. Founder &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/meet-hinge-and-its-founder-justin-mcleod-2014-10"&gt;Justin McLeod has said&lt;/a&gt; that it finished out its first year with only a few thousand users and $32,000 in the bank. It didn’t see rapid user growth until 2014, relying heavily on marketing that distinguished it as the alternative to Tinder. While Tinder did its best to match users with strangers, Hinge proposed that it would be slightly less alienating and confusing if your matches were based on mutual Facebook friends. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="aQG9vG"&gt;By 2015, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/3/19/8257357/hinge-explained"&gt;it was a hit&lt;/a&gt;, and McLeod was claiming it arranged 35,500 dates and 1,500 relationships a week. But the app was exceedingly ugly, and fell under criticism for appealing to an elitist urge to abandon the masses of Tinder and migrate to something more insular. It didn’t seem like something the company was trying to hide. A Hinge spokesperson &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/3/19/8257357/hinge-explained"&gt;told Vox’s Dylan Matthews&lt;/a&gt; at the time: “Hinge users are 99 percent college-educated, and the most popular industries include banking, consulting, media, and fashion. We recently found 35,000 users attended Ivy League schools.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="WYgNJq"&gt;And though the user base was growing, McLeod &lt;a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2016/10/hinge-relaunch-swipe-dating-apocalypse"&gt;told Vanity Fair&lt;/a&gt; that user satisfaction was dropping steadily. The company surveyed its users at the end of 2015 and found that 54 percent of its users reported “feeling lonely” after swiping, and that 81 percent had never found a long-term relationship. Hinge &lt;a href="https://thedatingapocalypse.com/"&gt;published its findings&lt;/a&gt; with a buzzy press push, calling it “The Dating Apocalypse.” The app got a huge visual overhaul, and it was relaunched in October 2016 with a $7 monthly fee meant to weed out the unserious. The new profiles included both photos and “icebreakers” — a range of personal questions from which users could select three to answer and display on their profiles. Most importantly, they were in arranged in a vertical scroll. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="xUPhrL"&gt;“We’ve swiped left on swiping,” the company &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@Hinge/in-november-2015-a-team-of-20-decided-to-take-a-successful-mainstream-product-rebuild-it-from-the-a72f9155c6eb"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;. “Instead of … racking up matches, people engage with the rich stories on your profile for more human conversations. It’s like Instagram profiles for dating.” And then: “$7 is less than your monthly Netflix or Spotify subscription, and nowhere near the cost of eHarmony ($60/month) or Match.com ($42/month). But it’s enough to make sure everyone is on the same page and not just using Hinge for entertainment.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="YjJ8VX"&gt;But within a month, it was &lt;a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/social-media/hinge-relationship-app/"&gt;offering some users&lt;/a&gt; lifetime free memberships, and by 2017, the free tier was back for everyone. Today, the main differences between the free and premium versions are the filtering options. The free app lets users filter for gender, location, age, height, ethnicity, and religion. Hinge Preferred — which is still $7 a month — adds additional filters for politics, drinking, smoking, drug use, whether someone has children, and whether they want children. It also comes with unlimited likes and access to “Hinge Experts” to help design your profile. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="qXHBg1"&gt;While Tinder can boast that it’s the top-grossing dating app and the second-top-grossing app overall in the app store, &lt;a href="https://hingeapp.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/sections/115001226387-Hinge-Overview"&gt;Hinge’s website&lt;/a&gt; brags that it’s the “mobile-first” dating app mentioned most often in The New York Times wedding section. (Not doing much for charges of elitism there, but it’s catchy.) That’s not the only way Hinge is different from Tinder — it collects better data. It’s a more robust app and knows more about its users. It lets them set “Dealbreakers” on certain filters, emphasizing just how serious they are about never dating a person of a different religion or a certain height. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;aside id="y9Yo7B"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How the Tinder algorithm actually works","url":"https://www.vox.com/2019/2/7/18210998/tinder-algorithm-swiping-tips-dating-app-science"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="NjoJjZ"&gt;It uses what it refers to as a “machine learning algorithm” to pick out one person per day as your &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/11/17560352/hinge-most-compatible-dating-machine-learning-match-recommendation"&gt;Most Compatible&lt;/a&gt;, and prods conversations forward with an “anti-ghosting” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/20/16801696/hinge-ghosting-avoid-feature-your-turn-accidental-ghost"&gt;Your Turn feature&lt;/a&gt;. Most notably, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/16/17979712/hinge-we-met-dating-rating-app"&gt;in October 2018&lt;/a&gt;, Hinge launched “We Met,” which asks users to give feedback on the real-life dates they’d been on. This information is supposedly used to improve the matchmaking algorithm, and the &lt;a href="https://hingeapp.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360010692913-What-is-We-Met-"&gt;Hinge site &lt;/a&gt;states, “What we learn from ‘We Met’ will only be used to improve the algorithm and ensure that the Hinge community remains safe and respectful.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="FsZDcx"&gt;Nevertheless, tons of data about the people who chose a middle ground between the ruthless swipe game of Tinder and the serious business of Match.com is valuable for Match, and could potentially be used to steer product decisions throughout its portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h3 id="JwjxJO"&gt;Bumble is the one that got away, and Match Group’s last remaining major competitor … until Facebook Dating&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p id="Xp9mct"&gt;Match CEO Mandy Ginsberg explained Match’s acquisition of Hinge by saying it’s “highly relevant, particularly among urban, educated millennial women looking for relationships.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="HbHabD"&gt;An interesting and somewhat pointed choice of words given Match Group’s failed attempt to acquire Bumble — the women-first swiping app led by Tinder co-founder Whitney Wolfe Herd in 2014, around the time Herd was &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/whitney-wolfe-settles-sexual-harassment-tinder-lawsuit-1-million-2014-11"&gt;settling a sexual harassment lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; with her former employer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="5RrM3Q"&gt;Match Group &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/whitney-wolfe-settles-sexual-harassment-tinder-lawsuit-1-million-2014-11"&gt;sued Bumble&lt;/a&gt; in March 2018 for stealing its intellectual property — i.e., Tinder’s swiping functionality. Ten days later, Bumble filed &lt;a href="https://www.recode.net/2018/3/28/17174986/bumble-match-group-lawsuit-fraud-400-million-acquisition-suing"&gt;its own patent infringement suit&lt;/a&gt;, saying that Match Group pretended to be interested in an acquisition of the company in the summer of 2017 only to gain access to privileged information and steal trade secrets, as well as “[chill] the market for an investment in Bumble.” Bumble also bought &lt;a href="https://www.recode.net/2018/3/20/17141308/bumble-match-group-new-york-times-ad-lawsuit-acquisition"&gt;an entire page of the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; and used it to call Match Group a “bully,” adding, “We swipe left on your multiple attempts to buy us, copy us, and, now, to intimidate us.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div id="9UOQlw"&gt;
            &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
            &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Swiping left on bullies and right on kindness, respect, and equality — today and every day. &lt;a href="https://t.co/CaYPKOCyL0"&gt;pic.twitter.com/CaYPKOCyL0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Bumble (@bumble) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bumble/status/976259611958349824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p id="e86FOg"&gt;Bumble later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/2/18056360/bumble-tinder-match-lawsuit-400-million"&gt;dropped its countersuit&lt;/a&gt;, but it did nothing to improve relations between the two companies. Match accused Bumble of engineering the entire drama “[a]s a hook to begin promoting the fact that Bumble was looking into conducting an Initial Public Offering on the New York Stock Exchange.” Bumble told The Verge it still believed Match was “bent on trying to impair the very business it was so desperate to buy.” This isn’t exactly the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/8/26/6067663/this-is-ubers-playbook-for-sabotaging-lyft"&gt;dirtiest tech startup battle&lt;/a&gt; of the past 10 years, but it shouldn’t be overlooked. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="WP1tHj"&gt;Nor should Match Group’s consolidation of power and arguable stifling of competition, even though that’s unlikely to concern the Federal Trade Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="ZvB9yV"&gt;“For dating startups, resistance against IAC is futile,” Wired’s Issie Lapowsky&lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/2014/07/howaboutwe/"&gt; wrote in 2014&lt;/a&gt;, reflecting on the company’s acquisition of HowAboutWe — a New York-based company that had tried to avoid selling to Match Group by diversifying its revenue with an editorial arm. Two months later, the company had been sold to Match after all. In a&lt;a href="https://www.recode.net/2018/7/31/17635384/tinder-match-dating-swipe-mandy-ginsberg-ceo-recode-decode"&gt; 2018 interview&lt;/a&gt; with Recode’s Kara Swisher, Ginsberg, the Match CEO, pointed out that her company also owns OurTime, the most popular dating app specifically for people ages 50 and up; and BlackPeopleMeet, the most popular dating app specifically for black people; and has recently launched BLK “for young millennial African Americans,” as well as Chispa, “a big partnership with Univision to attract the Latino community.” &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="gDNK2d"&gt;She asserted that Match Group is growing its portfolio globally at all times, filling in gaps with acquisitions, and that, in the meantime, “Every person who’s 18, 19, 20 should be on Tinder … we really want to be integrated into people’s single social life, especially when they’re young.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="badPnr"&gt;Consolidation in the dating app industry does not look as urgent as consolidation in industries like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/4/17816572/tim-wu-facebook-regulation-interview-curse-of-bigness-antitrust"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/technology/monopoly-antitrust-lina-khan-amazon.html"&gt;online retail&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/attachments/competition-policy-guidance/overview_pharma_august_2018.pdf"&gt;pharmaceuticals&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/05/opinion/facebook-integration.html"&gt;if the FTC is busy&lt;/a&gt; working up the nerve and resources to do anything at all about Facebook, that’s definitely more important. Though, ironically, Facebook recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/20/17871690/facebook-dating-release-colombia-test"&gt;began testing&lt;/a&gt; its own dating app — undoubtedly the only new project in the space that could threaten Match’s dominance. Facebook already has the largest &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/explainer-what-exactly-is-the-social-graph-2012-3"&gt;map of social networks&lt;/a&gt; in human history, with more than 2 billion active users. We’re hurtling toward an increasingly monopolized future, where the only challenges come from other preexisting monopolies.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="8Wb8xe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p id="Je7LXr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/2/11/18220425/hinge-explained-match-group-tinder-dating-apps"/>
        <id>https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/2/11/18220425/hinge-explained-match-group-tinder-dating-apps</id>
        <author>
            <name>Kaitlyn Tiffany</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>
